How's it coming?
Very, very well.
It's a flurry of deliveries.
Feels like Christmas morning.
Ahh, it's exciting.
It's really coming together.
And I'd like to point out
that if you have
any understandable questions
about the price tag...
That sound? Quality.
At Pfizer, at Merck,
that unit would be right at home.
That goes for all of it.
Good. l want you
to have what you need.
Oh. Well,
I doff my proverbial cap
to you, sir. Ha-ha.
When do you think
we'll be up and running?
Within a month, l'd say.
Two weeks.
Or, yeah, two weeks.
Good. Very good.
By the way, that sample
you asked me to run?
I ran it, and it is quite good.
Thank you very much, Gale.
You can give that to Victor to discard.
Uh, sure.
Is that our competition?
I'm sorry?
The, uh...
It really is quite good.
The purity, of course, l'm speaking of,
speaking strictly in chemical terms.
And I can't, as of yet,
account for the blue color,
but if that is our competition,
we have our work cut out for us,
so to speak.
You don't have any competition, Gale,
not as far as l'm concerned.
After all, how pure can pure be?
Well, it can be pretty darn pure.
Mr. Fring, I can guarantee you
a purity of 96 percent.
I'm proud of that figure.
It's a hard-earned figure, 96.
However,
this other product is 99.
Maybe even
a touch beyond that.
I'd need an instrument
called a gas chromatograph
to say for sure,
but, um, that last 3 percent,
it may not sound like a lot,
but it is.
It's tremendous.
It's a tremendous gulf.
Gale, for our purposes,
96 percent will do just fine.
Please, don't let this trouble you.
Yeah. It's just...
I'd love to know
who synthesized it, is all.
A man who wants to work with me.
A trained chemist, like yourself.
But it won't happen.
I don't consider him a professional.
If he's not, I don't know
what that makes me.
I'm not trying
to talk myself out of a job--
With this person,
there are other considerations.
His is the best l've ever seen,
hands down.
And I look at this place
that you've built,
the money you're investing,
sparing no expense.
And I know...
I know that
you want the best.
6353 Juan Tabo. Apartment 6.
No, no. Eubank's west.
It's between Eubank and Spain,
but Mazatlan's closest.
I don't know. I just heard the one,
like, you know, a backfire,
a truck backfiring.
I came out of my apartment.
A couple came out.
No. No, nobody saw.
Did you guys see anybody?
Guys, did you--? l don't know
if they speak English too good.
I don't think they saw anybody.
It was just this one loud--
This very loud pop and that was all.
No arguing or like that.
So you guys good in directions there?
You want me to..?
They coming east or west?
If heading east, tell them there's
an Exxon on their left-hand side.
Then it's straight residential.
You want me to what? Yeah.
No. I'll stay on the line.
You know him?
We all heard this shot.
I don't think
you ought to go in there.
Mister, this is a crime scene.
You don't wanna touch anything.
Mister?
Mister, are you listening to me?
Little bastard.
Drive.
What the hell happened?
He's gone?
Look at me.
Gone?
You sure?
Gone. Splattered all over.
Oh, Jesus. Jesus. Oh, shit.
All right.
So...
Shit.
- All right, you do a sweep?
- Couldn't. People there.
People? He get himself
seen by these people?
What about you?
Yeah. So what?
Just another looky-loo.
I guess l'd better get this over with.
Hey.
Oh, jeez, I woke you up.
I woke you up.
No, no, no, it's okay.
I needed to get up anyway.
Are you coming in?
No. It's kind of my only time
to run errands.
I just needed to...
Ah.
I...
Sorry.
It's okay.
And thank you, bigtime,
as always.
They seem to be getting bigger
instead of smaller.
Not really sure
what that's all about.
Please, for God's sake,
tell me if this is getting
to be too much for you.
Absolutely not, okay?
It's absolutely fine.
Okay.
Does this mean
what I think it means? Heh.
What?
You and Walt?
His car is in the driveway.
It's not a state secret.
I-- Oh. All right. Okay.
I'm not pressing. I just...
I think that it's great.
That's all, all right?
I'm out of here.
Okay.
Oh, hey. A big howdy-do
to Mr. l'm-Not-Here.
in Albuquerque today.
But you know what? It always is when
you have 330 days of sunshine a year.
On morning commute,
northbound 25,
we've got a two-car accident
on the right shoulder.
You gotta be careful.
Also, from the west side,
we've got another accident,
Paseo del Norte and Second Street.
That one's on the left shoulder,
so be on the lookout.
That's a look at your
morning commute on Coyote 1 02.5.
Oh, hey.
Breakfast?
Yeah.
Yeah? Okay.
All right. What you want?
All right, look.
So I make it 1 0 to 9,
which means--
Shut up.
Which means we need to start
a cook in the next 1 0 minutes
to keep to our schedule.
Gus' schedule.
And as angry as he may be,
I don't believe he's willing
to forfeit an entire batch.
That just might make him angrier.
Come on, Mike. Let us cook.
Isn't that
what this whole thing is about?
That's right, genius.
Watch me.
We ain't missing no cook.
We're closed.
Closed.
Saul Goodman
and Associates.
I'll see if he's in.
Please hold.
Saul, Skyler White calling.
Saul.
Saul, Skyler White on the line.
Hey.
Skyler White.
What the hell does she want?
He's nowhere to be found.
I called his condo,
every number l have.
Yeah, I'm sure he's fine.
You're sure?
As in, you know where he is?
Heh, heh. I'm not the man's keeper,
but Walt's a big boy. He'll turn up.
Mr. Goodman,
something is going on.
Why would he leave his car
in my driveway?
People carpool to work, right?
It's good for the environment.
He carpools?
He carpools to his job at a meth lab?
Hey, whoa. Oh-ho,
you're breaking up there.
I didn't quite catch that last...
Whew!
You're a Chatty Cathy today.
Okay, do you know anything?
Anything at all? Please,
I'm looking for some help here.
Look, Walter is fine, okay?
I guarantee that, hundred percent.
One hundred percent.
You got a passport, right?
Yeah. Albuquerque.
I'm in Nob Hill.
I need the number
for a locksmith.
I don't know. Pick one.
You sure there's nothing?
No, it's not even me. lt's state law.
Are you sure there isn't
some sort of--? I don't know.
No. Nothing.
Maybe a car registration.
That would have your address.
No, but l can't even get in my car.
My car keys were on the same ring.
My God, my credit cards, my--
It's all right, sweetheart.
My driver's license, my checkbook.
I have to start canceling all that.
My whole life was in that purse
and he just cut it right
off my shoulder.
We could've been stabbed.
I'm sorry, really.
But without proof of residency...
I can take you down to my shop.
You're welcome to wait,
file a police report.
I can't believe this.
I cannot believe this day.
I know. It's just, it's the law.
Oh, my God. My medication.
I bet it's gone.
Oh, God, not now, not this.
Gotta call the pharmacy.
Are you okay?
Please, just-- Please, just take her.
Please. Just take her, please.
Oh. Oh, God.
Not now. No. Not now.
Oh, you're a lifesaver. Truly.
Here you go, sweetheart.
Oh, there you go.
Um-- How do you--?
How do you wanna deal with the bill?
I-- Unfortunately,
all my cash was taken so...
That's fine. We'll mail it to you.
Will you? You know
where l live, right?
Sir, again, thank you so much. Really.
Yeah.
Hey there. l'm back.
How was PT?
I heard it was very good.
Mm.
I'm really liking this new therapist.
He keeps me in the loop,
always has time
for a phone call. It's...
I like it.
So?
Tell me all about it.
I heard you broke
new ground today.
I broke new ground?
That's what he said. Tell me.
I walked 1 6 feet in 20 minutes,
which is up from
my 1 5 and a half yesterday.
And this much less shit
in my pants.
So, yeah, Marie, if you and him and
everybody in America took a vote,
changed the meaning
of the English language,
yeah, I guess
I "broke new ground."
Well, call it a figure of speech,
but l am seeing progress.
Definite progress.
You're ordering a new rock?
I'm bidding on a new mineral.
It's a nice one.
What? lt's pretty.
I need the thing.
Okay, numero uno.
Dos.
Okay.
It has all those pretty
little crystals. l like that.
Okay.
All right, I just wanna go on record,
we should all be wearing masks.
We should be wearing masks.
Bet he forgets the aluminum.
Guaranteed.
Guarantee he forgets.
Mm-hm. Oh, you don't know
what the hell you're doing, do you?
You forgot the aluminum.
One of the first steps in the...
Son of a bitch.
All right,
let's talk about Gale Boetticher.
He was a good man
and a good chemist,
and I cared about him.
He didn't deserve
what happened to him.
He didn't deserve it at all.
But l'd shoot him again
tomorrow and the next day
and the day after that.
When you make it Gale versus me,
or Gale versus Jesse,
Gale loses, simple as that.
This is on you, Gus.
Not me, not Jesse.
Gale's death is on you.
I mean, really,
what did you expect me to do,
just simply roll over
and allow you to murder us?
That I wouldn't take measures,
extreme measures to defend myself?
Wrong.
Think again. And whatever it is
you're planning there,
whatever it is, the point
that you're trying to make here,
let me suggest
that you keep one thing in mind.
Without us,
without Jesse and myself,
you have no one
to make your product.
Certainly not him.
This person doesn't know
what the hell he's doing.
Been watching him for weeks.
I know every step of his cook.
Oh.
Do you really? You?
Really?
Oh, so please tell me.
Catalytic hydrogenation,
is it protic or aprotic?
Because l forget.
If our reduction isn't stereospecific,
how can our product be pure?
I mean, is 1-phenyl-1-hydroxy-
2-methylamino-propane,
containing, of course,
chiral centers
at carbons number one and two
on the propane chain?
Then reduction
to methamphetamine
eliminates which chiral center
is it again?
Because l forgot.
Come on, help me out, professor.
Gus.
We're here. Come on.
Let us work.
All his bullshit aside,
it's called a cook.
Everything comes down
to following a recipe.
Simple, complicated,
it doesn't matter.
The steps never change,
and I know every step.
Oh, is that what you want?
This short-order cook?
You're not flipping hamburgers.
What happens when
you get a bad barrel of precursor?
How would you
even know it?
And what happens in the summer
when the humidity rises
and your product goes cloudy?
How would you
guard against that, huh?
Gus.
You do this, all you'll have left
is an $8 million hole in the ground.
This lab,
this equipment is useless
without us.
Without Jesse and myself,
you have no new product.
You have no income.
Your people out there will not be paid.
Your distribution chain collapses.
Without us,
you have nothing.
You kill me, you have nothing.
You kill Jesse,
you don't have me.
You won't do this.
You're too smart.
You can't afford to do this.
Please.
Let us just go back to work.
We're here.
Let us work.
We're ready to go to work.
We'll just pick up
right where we left off.
Well?
Get back to work.
Listen,
we'll just lay this down.
Put him in feet first.
Grab his shoe.
Here. Wait, wait, wait.
Just lift him up. There. All right.
Oh, God.
You push that way,
I'll hold him in.
Okay, ready? One...
Oh, shit.
Wait, wait. Wait.
Forget that. Okay.
Come on. Up.
Get down.
Okay, okay.
I never use this stuff.
Are you sure it'll do the job?
Trust us.
♪ There was once a time ♪
♪ When l didn't mind ♪
♪ If l never saw the light ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ l can truly say ♪
Here you go, hon.
Get you anything else?
No, I'm good. Thanks.
♪ Oh, l don't mind ♪
♪ If my hair starts turning gray ♪
♪ There's not much that I can do ♪
♪ Mm-hm ♪
♪ Long behind me l have
Left my younger days ♪♪
How you doing?
No, I mean, you know,
how are you doing?
You did the only thing
that you could.
I hope you understand that.
Thoughts?
Any thoughts on what
our next move might be?
What next move?
Our next move.
Our next move, given the fact
that at the first opportunity,
Gus will kill us.
What, that wasn't
an opportunity just now?
Seemed like a damn good
opportunity to me.
No, no.
Golden, I would say.
We bought ourselves some time,
yes, but...
The question is how much.
He'll be looking for another chemist.
He's not gonna find another chemist.
Hm.
Where is he gonna find
another chemist?
It's not just about somebody
being able to run a lab that big.
Someone he can trust,
someone he knows
will keep their mouths shut.
Yeah. Good luck with that.
Bet it took him years to find Gale.
Heh. Bet he's sorry now.
Are you sure you're okay?
Now we all understand each other.
Right?
What do you mean?
I mean, him and us, we get it.
We're all on the same page.
And what page is that?
The one that says:
"lf I can't kill you,
you'll sure as shit wish
you were dead."
Yo, excuse me.
Thanks.
- Here.
- Thank you, sir.
Have a good one.
Thanks.
Hi.
Um, it's parked
over on Amsden.
Junior was about to get up
and he would've seen it,
so I wanted to avoid
a lot of questions.
Smart.
Well.
Kenny Rogers.
Yeah.
You okay?
Right as rain.
Do you have your keys?
Yeah.
Um... It's parked three blocks
down on the right.
Yeah.
♪ The truth is that
I never shook my shadow ♪
♪ Every day it's trying
To trick me into doing battle ♪
♪ Calling out "faker"
Only get me rattled ♪
♪ Want to pull me back
Behind the fence with the cattle ♪
♪ Building your lenses
Digging your trenches ♪
♪ Put me on the front line
Leave me with a dumb mind ♪
♪ With no defenses
But your defense is ♪
♪ If you can't stand to feel the pain
Then you are senseless ♪♪