So how's it look?
Meaning, do l see it?
Yes.
Do you see it?
Basically, any lawman
worth his salt is gonna
spot that, yeah.
Assuming that's a deal breaker?
Yes, it's a deal breaker.
Well, if stealth
is what you're aspiring to,
you best go with
something more compact.
Thirty-eight Special.
Snub nose.
Got a concealed hammer
so it don't catch on your belt
when you draw.
Tried and true.
No nonsense about it.
Five shots.
Yeah.
Automatic has how many?
Ten in the mag,
one in the chamber.
If you can't get it done with five,
you're into spray and pray,
in which case, l wouldn't count
on another six closing the deal.
You load that with
1 58-grain hollow points
instead of standard wadcutters,
it's got plenty of stopping power.
Can't get more dependable
than a wheel gun.
Try it on with this.
That snubbie will conceal up
real nice if you carry it IWB.
Little harder to draw from,
but there's no substitute
if you're intent
on fooling a vigilant eye.
Comes in polymer too.
I prefer the feel of leather.
Old school, I guess.
Well, um...
Sure it's on
the correct side?
If you're right-handed, it is.
I don't know, ma--
Are you sure?
Maybe it'll feel better
on the left side.
General rule,
you don't wanna cross-draw.
Not unless you're gonna be sitting.
You know, store clerks,
card gamers and such.
Uh-huh.
Either way,
you're gonna wanna
practice your draw. A lot.
Because if you're all fingers,
well, it might could be him
keeping the peace instead of you.
Catch my drift?
What's this?
That is why you're gonna
pay me five times
what you'd pay
your neighborhood gun store.
Serial number's been filed off.
So to state the obvious,
I don't wanna be caught
with this on me.
No. To state the obvious,
you don't.
You know, mister, l've been
providing my services
for the past 30-odd years.
You'd think I'd learn better
than to ask a man his business,
especially not one referred
by the lawyer.
But l do feel the urge
to ask you,
are we strictly talking defense
here?
Yes, absolutely.
Defense.
Why?
Because if it's just
personal protection,
aside from a bucket of money,
you'd save yourself
a potential felony two-spot
for carrying a weapon
with a defaced serial number
if you buy it legally.
But if you did have to use it,
wouldn't it still be better to use one
that couldn't be traced?
This is the West, boss.
New Mexico's not
a retreat jurisdiction.
Man steps to you bent
on doing you harm,
you got every right to plant
your feet and shoot to kill.
Some call it a moral right, and I do
include myself within that class.
All this to say,
I'm happy to take your money.
But if you're not a convicted felon,
you might best be advised
to bear your arms
within the confines of the law.
It's for defense.
Defense.
I'll take it.
Thanks, Bonnie.
♪ Money, money, money, money ♪
♪ l get that ♪
♪ Fast money ♪
♪ And the ♪
♪ Fly cars ♪
♪ l get that ♪
♪ Fast money ♪
♪ And the ♪
♪ Fly cars ♪
♪ Money, money, money, money ♪
♪ l'm rolling in the ♪
♪ l get that ♪
♪ Fast money ♪
♪ And the ♪
♪ Fly cars ♪
♪ Get the money, man ♪
♪ D/R Period ♪
♪ Get the money, man
Get the money, man ♪
♪ Get the money, man ♪
♪ Come through with the flops now
'Cause I got the top down ♪
♪ Agent try to come through
Pop, pop, pop, pop, pop you down ♪
♪ Shorty moving in my hand
Million dollar diamond ring ♪
♪ All them ladies love a ♪
♪ King ♪
♪ So l gotta sidestep
Move with the booties, man ♪
♪ Ride for the team ♪
♪ And you know
We get that money, man ♪
♪ Pull up to a wholesale ♪
Jesse.
What's up, brother?
Dude, sounds like an earthquake
out there.
Uh, new sound system.
- Check it out.
- Whoa!
Bodacious subwoofers, yo.
Serious cannons.
Eighteen-inchers, six of them.
Aluminum cones, so they're
really, really, like, sonically neutral.
Tweeters are killer too.
Dig all them lines jumping
around. Psychedelic.
♪ Money, money, money, money ♪
Kind of, like,
just wanna stare at them.
Heh. Yeah, man,
totally makes me wanna crank
old Sabbath and blaze one.
It's got, like,
parametric equalization.
Automatically adjusts
the levels to changes in
air pressure and whatnot.
It's totally digital.
Vacuum tube amp,
which is, by far, the best,
anti-distortion-wise.
Hits 1 20 decibels
without breaking a sweat.
Hold onto your hats, bitches.
♪ There's money
Money everywhere ♪
♪ Money, money, money, money ♪
♪ l'm rolling in the ♪
♪ l get that ♪♪
♪ We can undress if you're into me ♪
♪ Up in the club ♪
♪ These ladies are stacked
They drinkin' it up ♪
♪ You know how we connect
Up in the club ♪
Hey, man, l saw Andrea
at a meeting yesterday.
She asked about you.
♪ So pass me a double Crown
Corona we sipping now ♪
♪ l'm looking at her like, "Wow"
She drinkin' a Lowenbrau ♪
♪ Must be a different breed
A chick that I'd like to meet ♪
♪ So then I walk over and say
"What in the hell is your name?" ♪
Thanks, man, but, um,
1 2 steps and all that.
Seriously?
♪ Don't you know
I'm a freaky creature? ♪
♪ So if you wanna learn
I'd be glad to teach ya ♪
♪ Champagne
Sippin' orange juice and Roq-a ♪
♪ Get you all wet, then stick it
Then rock ya ♪
♪ Up in the club ♪
♪ These ladies are stacked ♪
♪ They drinkin' it up ♪
♪ You know how we connect
Up in the club ♪
Maybe just a little bump.
♪ You already know what's next
Now throw your hands up in the air ♪
♪ Club hoppers everywhere
Wave like you just do not care ♪♪
Left 4 Deae, yo. Bitches get all
cranial when you cap them
in the head. It's like, "Booyah!"
No, no, no, man. Resieent Evil 4
takes it by a long shot.
Oh, please, brother. You're fronting.
No, seriously.
That chick,
the one you gotta rescue?
She's smoking, bro.
And then you're, like,
the last undead dude on earth.
How can you not be dipping
into that?
Talk about inspiring a brother
to kick zombie ass.
They're trying to eat your brain.
A dude don't need no more motivation.
Fair point, l guess.
Okay, okay, okay.
Call of Duty: World at War,
zombie mode.
Now, that's the bomb, man.
Think on it, bro.
They're not just zombies.
They're Nazi zombies.
Nazi zombies. Pssh.
Yeah, man. SS Waffen troopers too,
which are like the baddest ass Nazis
of the whole Nazi family.
What difference does it make what
their job was when they was living?
Dude, you are so
historically retarded.
Nazi zombies don't wanna
eat you just because
they're craving the protein.
They do it because--
They do it because
they hate Americans, man.
Talibans. They're the Talibans
of the zombie world.
I played the game.
They ain't exactly fleet of foot.
I'm saying,
where's the challenge?
The zombies in Left 4 Deae
clock a respectable 40.
You gotta lead them.
They're not even zombies.
They're just infected.
They got, like, this rage virus,
amps them up
like they been smoking the schwag.
Apples and oranges, bro.
Totally unfair to compare the two.
♪ You ain't nothin'
But a hoochie mama ♪
Yo, Jesse, where do you
come out on all this?
Ha, ha. Oh...
Agree. Totally.
♪ Hood rat, hood rat
Hoochie mama ♪♪
Did that just happen?
Damn, man.
It's quiet.
You know what
this place needs?
♪ Say "unga, bunga, bunga," G ♪
♪ Unga, bunga, bunga, G ♪
♪ Say "unga, bunga, binga, bunga
Binga, binga, bunga" ♪
♪ That's my sound rippin' through
Your speakers ♪
♪ Make you scrape up
All your sneakers ♪
♪ Do the break-dance on your head ♪
♪ Doing backflips in the pit ♪
♪ Ring, ding, dong ♪
♪ Ringa-ding, ding, ding, dong ♪
♪ Flav, stop this crazy thing ♪
♪ Flav, drop this song you sing ♪
♪ Say "unga, bunga, bunga," G ♪
♪ Unga, bunga, bunga, G ♪
♪ Say "unga, bunga, binga, bunga" ♪
♪ Unga, bunga, binga, bunga ♪
♪ Say "unga, bunga, bunga," G ♪♪
You okay?
Fine.
Can't you sleep?
Actually, yes, Marie.
This is me sleeping.
What's it look like?
It looks like you're looking
at a rock...
at 2:24 in the morning.
This is not a rock,
this is a mineral,
for, like, the 1 0th time.
Okay.
Got it.
Blue corundum,
to be precise.
Blue corundum.
Well, it's very pretty.
It's encrusted with igneous
biotite in a mica schist.
Would you like some more detail?
Because l can give it to you.
You can keep acting
like you give the first shit--
Hank.
Found in the Central Cordillera
of lrian Jaya.
Blue corundum.
I'm just saying...
It's 2 in the morning.
I'm just asking if maybe--
You know, last I counted,
Marie, there were four
bedrooms in this house.
You know, I mean, if l'm
keeping you awake and all.
- You've reached Walter White.
- Please state your name,
number and reason for your call.
Thank you.
Walt?
Hello? Walt?
Okay, Walt,
could you call me back, please?
Hank's bills are really starting
to pile up here.
And in the meantime,
I haven't received a check from you
in quite a while.
Second order of business
is the car wash.
Unh! God!
So it's time to take the next step here.
We need to look
into buying this car wash while we--
Skyler, what are you doing?
What do you mean?
Wait, are you screening all my calls?
No, no, no, I'm just--
What are you thinking leaving
a message like that on my machine?
What are you--?
What did I say?
You just left recorded proof
of our intention to buy a car wash.
Now, you think that was wise?
Proof of our what?
What are you talking about?
Skyler, we should not even be
mentioning the words "car wash"
on the phone at all. Period.
Walt, it is a car wash,
not a brothel.
I mean, if we can't even say what it is,
why are we buying it at all?
Ugh, God, look, Skyler,
please, just--
Hey, Mom.
Hey, hon.
Look, there's some cereal
on the breakfast table.
I'm telling you,
if you're not willing
to pull the trigger,
I'm more than happy
to call Goodman myself.
No, no, no, I will handle it, okay?
I could so use
a brain transplant right now.
Yeah. I'm going to work.
Wake up, bitch.
Huh!
Damn.
Argh.
You're way too sensitive
about your zone, bro.
Argh. Come on, man.
Clean-up time.
Right on. Least we can do.
Hey, the hell with cleaning up.
Just go out and get everybody
some breakfast.
Stock up on liquor
while you're at it.
Keep this party going.
I mean it, yo.
I mean, I want this place
kicking harder than a sensei
when l get back.
- All right.
- You got it, bro.
♪ Yo, drop it ♪
♪ Go, nigga, raise hell ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Raise hell ♪
Come on, damn it!
Wake up and party!
♪ The new single, kid
Get your shipment ♪
♪ Catch this new slug
From the M.O.P. hit list ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm for the cars
For the clubs, for the Jeeps ♪
♪ For the fellas on the corner
Posted up 20 deep ♪
♪ Hold it down ♪
♪ Home team ♪♪
Uh...
Hello.
Yo, you the new guy?
Yeah.
You got something for me?
Two hundred and one point six.
What's the count?
Two-oh-one point six.
Give it a second weigh,
if you would, please.
New policy.
What, Walter?
Where's Gus?
Why?
Because l would like
to speak with him.
Because the way we left things,
I would like the chance
to clear the air.
Hm.
What?
Walter,
you're never gonna see him again.
Oh, look who woke up hungry.
Are you hungry?
Yeah, that's good.
Drink that up.
Just a little longer,
okay, my sweetie?
Okay?
Okay...
There you go.
Okay, now.
The Dodge gets a detail,
and the Corolla
gets a hand wax.
Right? Hand wax.
Okay.
Ah. Hello. Hello.
Just a few more minutes
then we're on our way home.
Okay, my sweet girl?
Mama's just doing her work here.
Mama's doing her work.
Way to go, Hank.
Come on, way to soldier up.
You're doing it. Come on.
Another few yards.
- Dig.
- Unh!
Argh! Jesus.
Look at you.
Way to go, honey.
Come on.
Come on, Hank.
Keep it going.
Just ten more steps.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
- Six.
You're almost there, Hank.
All right, buddy.
That's what I call
kicking some ass.
Oh, that was
awesome, babe. Ha.
Hells, yeah!
Very nice.
Yeah!
Hey!
You're a good man, Chuck.
Thanks.
It's an honor, my friend.
Same time tomorrow?
Damned straight,
if l'm still alive.
- Great session.
- Lots of positive energy.
Lots.
It's just--
It's so great to see that.
It's just...
Yeah.
One day at a time.
All we can do.
I know. It's just...
You've got a real way with him.
It's...
You wanna go full time?
We've got a spare bedroom.
Heh. I'll see you tomorrow.
Wow, you were
so strong today.
Did you work up an appetite?
I'm sure you did.
Listen, I was thinking
about cooking tonight, so--
Marie.
Get out.
♪ Get down ♪
- Oh, yo, about time.
- Oh, my God.
Yo, what's up with the pie, man?
It ain't cut.
Yeah, right. That's the gimmick.
What gimmick?
This place, they don't cut their pizza,
they pass the savings on to you.
How much can it be
to cut a damn pizza?
Maybe it's, like, democratic, bro.
You know,
cut your own Christmas tree,
cut your own pizza.
Yeah, it's democratic.
- What am I supposed to do with this?
- Don't sweat it.
You got some, like, scissors?
I will cut this bitch up good.
Yo, come in.
Hey, would you...?
Gotta figure, you make, like,
1 0 million pizzas a year.
Each pizza takes, like,
1 0 seconds to cut.
In man-hours, that's...
I don't know.
Heh, heh, heh.
A lot.
- Hey, Jesse?
- Huh?
You got, um...
Yeah.
♪ Get down ♪
So, uh, how you doing?
I'm dealing.
How's Brock?
Good. He's, uh...
Brock, honey, wait in the car, okay?
Let the grown-ups speak.
- Go on, little man.
- We'll catch up later.
Guess you know
I've been calling.
Yeah. Um--
I'm really busy at work and...
Jesse, l'm not here to
make you come up with excuses.
You got other things going on.
I get it.
There's just one thing
you and me gotta talk about.
And that's this.
After Tomas was murdered,
two dudes,
bangers he used to hang with,
get run over.
One of them shot in the head.
Same night, I get this in my mailbox.
This was you?
You know what?
Whatever it is you had to do
with my brother's killers,
I don't wanna know.
But you gotta tell me one thing:
Is someone gonna come
looking for this?
No.
What exactly am I supposed
to do with this?
Use it to get you and Brock out
of that shit hole of a neighborhood.
Or you can go out
and spend it on glass
and I'd have no way
of stopping you.
But l gotta believe
you won't do that.
Whoo!
♪ Get down ♪♪
Go home, Walter.
How you doing?
Hi.
Ton of bricks?
Rocks.
You, uh, want me to
wheel them inside?
Thank you.
Marie, is that my minerals?
Yes, Hank.
How many boxes?
I don't know.
Three, four hundred.
A million.
I don't know.
Did you check them
for damage?
Oh, my God.
They're rocks, Hank.
No, they're minerals.
Jesus, Marie.
I got some geodes coming
that are very delicate, all right?
I'll not accept any boxes
that have damage.
Those delivery jagoffs,
I'm not getting ass-raped
by those bastards.
Just...
Honey, would you check?
Just check, please?
Hey, you, too much wax.
Stop wasting it.
Look, tell your brother
that if he doesn't show up tomorrow
I'm gonna have to fire him.
So now, go back.
And no more excuses.
Mr. Wolynetz,
my name is Skyler White.
How do you do?
You wanna buy my car wash?
I do.
And I am prepared to talk numbers
right now, if you'd like.
You think this is an easy job?
You are willing to get down
on your hands and knees
and scrub like a housemaid,
with all the chemicals
eating into your nice skin
and stinging in your eyes?
Well, I know a thing or two
about scrubbing.
Any other advice for me?
Because l am serious about this.
Good.
I am serious too.
I have worked 30 years on building
this business from nothing,
with my own hands
and my own sweat and blood.
I can appreciate that. Truly.
So with that in mind,
is there a figure
you can quote me?
One which you think would--
Ten million dollars.
Well, let's try 879,000.
Where do you come up
with this number?
You pull it from your behind?
On a typical day,
you average 1 9 cars per hour.
Extrapolating, l added
the extra revenues for
hand waxes and detailing.
Subtracted your overhead
in salary,
maintenance,
operating fees, depreciation,
which I obtained from businesses
in the Albuquerque area,
giving me an estimate
of your annual cash flow here.
I applied industry-standard multiplier,
added market value of your real estate.
Giving me a total
estimated value of $829,000.
On top of which I generously
added an extra $50,000.
So as not to be insulting.
Twenty million dollars.
Okay, Mr. Wolynetz, this--
This is the price for Walter White.
Ah.
Oh, yes. You don't think
I know who you are?
I remember.
Well, I have not pretended to be a--
Your husband,
he quit without giving me notice.
He broke my air fresheners,
he cursed at me and grabbed himself.
And now he wants
to buy my car wash.
But he's not man enough
to come in here and face me himself.
Instead he sends his woman.
Excuse me.
Walter White wants
to buy my car wash.
The price he pays
is 20 million dollars.
Now, please leave.
Have you recently lost a loved one
in an aviation disaster?
Have you suffered injury,
shock to the senses
or property damage
as a result of airplane debris
or, God forbid, falling body parts?
Then call me, Saul Goodman.
It goes without saying,
that the six, seven,
perhaps eight-figure cash settlement
that l can win for you
will never fill the hole in your heart
caused by your tragic loss.
But you deserve justice.
So if you want to tip the scales
back in your favor,
better call Saul.
- Saul Goodman, attorney-at-law.
505-503-4455.
We are just about ready to go...
You might wanna learn
how to tail better
if you're planning
on making a habit of it.
May I buy you a drink?
Next round, when you're done.
Why not? You make
a hell of a lot more than l do.
Another round for him,
and I'll have the same.
No ice.
I feel like I need
to explain myself.
There were some actions
that I took which I want you
to understand.
I didn't want any of this
to happen.
Everything l did,
I did out of loyalty to my partner.
And then, later,
of course,
purely out of self-defense.
I hope you can appreciate that.
Just like I appreciated that...
I appreciate that when
you were going to kill me,
you were simply following orders.
I get that. Completely.
And I harbor no ill will.
Well, there's a load
off my mind.
Mike, I'm trying to tell you--
I get it.
Fine.
Drink up, Walter.
Hell of a last couple of weeks.
Makes a man wonder exactly
where he stands.
I mean, I cannot be alone
in feeling this way.
Not after what happened to Victor.
So, what's with the piece?
Right hip,
inside your waistband.
I noticed it the other day
at the lab. You wear it
if it makes you feel better.
But if push comes to shove,
it's not gonna help.
Mike, do I have to come right out
and say this?
You and I...
we're in the same boat.
Drink your drink.
If it happened to Victor,
it could happen to you.
And what the hell was that,
anyway? Hm?
A message?
He cuts a man's throat
just to send a message?
You won, Walter.
You got the job.
Do yourself a favor
and learn to take yes for an answer.
Yeah, I got the job.
But for how long?
Get me in a room with him.
Mike, just get me in a room,
and I'll do the rest.
You done?
Yeah.
Whoa.
Thanks for the drink.
♪ Paid a fee
Door, let me get in free ♪
Pinkman, man,
you know how to party, brother.
Epic. Epic.
- Seriously?
- Where you two going?
Jesse, l've been awake
for, like, three straight days.
I'm turning into a Sleestak.
So crash here.
It's not like I ain't got
the space.
Yeah, that's cool and all,
but l think I got, like, this cat.
Think I'm, like,
supposed to feed it.
Whatever, you little bitch.
What about you?
You sticking
or do I gotta flip you over,
check you for a slizz?
Bro, l'm kind of
pushing flowers here, yo.
I ain't proud of it,
but it's God's honest truth.
Hell, brother, you know
we got mad love for you.
Now that you're back
in the mix, it's, like,
nothing but good days ahead.
Plenty of time to pace it out,
is all l'm saying.
Yeah, man.
Totally.
I was thinking, like,
next week?
Yeah, sure, man. Next week.
We cool?
We are cool.
♪ Nightlife
Want me back by 9 ♪
♪ Finish up, exchange and ride ♪
♪ Put a lot into coup d'état
None of this is new to me ♪
♪ Fuckers thought
They'd play the part ♪
♪ Super Clark, change the scene
Likely dream, 'cept for the part ♪
♪ Pertaining to the talent ♪
♪ Them motherfucking money suckers
Chop 'em into salad ♪
♪ Ceiling with a pillow
Watching the prophecy drop ♪
♪ Somehow feeling halfway guilty
Sleeping the sympathy off ♪
♪ Pray for anarchist law
Blind mischivalrous pigs ♪
♪ You can't cuff up my wrist
If you can't find it ♪
♪ Di-- Di-- Di-- ♪
♪ Digital animal, freaky folks ♪
♪ Belly covered up
T-shirt, red tiger ♪
♪ Drool down the lip
Striped saber-toothed slimer ♪
♪ Dribble, spit, tip scale
Dirty dogma ♪
♪ Puppy love, block, Shaka
Trois ménage ♪
♪ Ninja, ninja, vanish, MO creep ♪
♪ Naughty fucking freaks
And bustin' techniques ♪
♪ East, west, battle best
Turn your bones to ashes ♪
♪ Send 'em to the kin
With the symbol on the package ♪
♪ Grow the fascination larger
Than there ever was ♪
♪ Walls kicked over, Berlin
Snap cameras ♪
♪ Gallagher, Petey G
Sledgehammer family ♪
♪ Dabble with insanity
Granted me the amnesty ♪
♪ l learned my lesson
Messin' up my life is not the way ♪
♪ To wreck it
Check the SM58 ♪
♪ Replace the vibe
Behind your face piece ♪
♪ Bass beats, your basics
Plus me is the combination ♪
♪ Known to defeat
The beast and his gatekeeper ♪
♪ Di-- Di-- Di-- ♪
♪ Digital animal, freaky folks ♪
♪ Digital animal ♪♪