No, no, no!
Hey.
Uh, it's me.
I just wanted to say that
I was thinking about you
and the kids, and, uh...
I love you.
Uh, it's me.
I just wanted to say that
I was thinking about you
and the kids, and, uh...
Morning.
Afternoon.
Oh, really? Jesus.
You shouldn't have
let me sleep.
You needed it.
Skyler, I don't entirely remember
what happened last night.
I mean, I might have said
some things that--
Did you know this
Gale Boetticher person?
Skyler, I can't even focus on--
Gale Boetticher.
Did you know him?
Heh.
My God. What--?
What exactly
did l say last night?
Just enough.
Did you work together?
Who killed him?
Was it the people you work for?
Definitely not.
Was it somebody who,
at some point,
might wanna do the same to you?
I seriously doubt it. No.
Ugh. God.
Oh, God.
I think I know what
happened last night, Walt.
Mm. I know exactly
what happened last night.
I drank too much wine.
You told Hank
that the man he was looking for
might still be out there.
That it might not be
this Boetticher after all.
And I was up all night,
wondering why you
would say that to him.
Mm. Because l was
drunk, Skyler.
No, but then
I was remembering
your black eye.
Your, uh, business disagreement
that you don't wanna talk about.
Look, I don't want to talk
about any of this. Ever.
The firewall, all right?
Church and state.
That's how we need
to approach this thing.
And then I remembered the message
you left me the other day,
when you said you loved me.
When I heard that,
I thought that maybe you--
I don't know, that you were regretting
what's happened between us.
And I get that.
After last night, l...
Walt, I think you're scared.
I think that message
was some kind of goodbye.
No, Skyler.
I think last night was a cry for help.
Oh, Jesus.
A cry for help?
I think some part of you
wants Hank to catch you.
Wow. That is just...
That is it exactly. Yes.
You're like
Dr. Joyce Brothers here.
God.
At least this
would all be over.
Yeah, yeah, oh, there's
a tremendous weight
just lifted off of me.
Now l understand myself.
Thank you. Thank you.
Walt, I've said it before.
If you are in danger,
we go to the police.
I don't wanna hear about the police.
I do not say that lightly.
I know what it could do
to this family.
But if it's the only real choice
we have, if it's either that
or you getting shot--
I don't wanna hear
about the police.
You're not some hardened criminal,
Walt. You are in over your head.
That's what we'll tell them,
the truth.
That is not the truth.
Of course it is.
A schoolteacher, cancer,
desperate for money.
We're done here.
Roped into working-- Unable to quit.
You told me that
yourself, Walt.
Jesus, what was I thinking?
Walt, please.
Let's both of us stop trying
to justify this whole thing
and admit you're in danger.
Who are you talking to right now?
Who is it you think you see?
Do you know
how much l make a year?
I mean, even if I told you,
you wouldn't believe it.
You know what would happen
if l decided to stop going in to work?
A business big enough
that it could be listed on
the NASDAQ goes belly up.
Disappears. It ceases
to exist without me. No.
You clearly don't know
who you're talking to,
so let me clue you in.
I am not in danger, Skyler.
I am the danger.
A guy opens his door and gets shot,
and you think that of me? No.
I am the one who knocks.
Look, I was...
Skyler?
Here we are, hm?
Just like you left it.
And where is your pretty wife?
She has other
business to attend to.
Well, like l say to her,
place sells as is.
Understand?
Yes, l understand.
Good, good.
I don't want her coming back
with more demands.
She gave me hard time
when we settled on price.
We're all on the same page,
Bogdan.
So here is everything
you need.
I keep very good files.
Thank you.
So you are
the boss now, huh?
You think you're ready?
Yes, l think so.
Being boss is tough.
I know you think
I was hard on you,
but you'll learn.
Being in charge is not easy.
It takes hard work.
You've seen me work hard, Bogdan.
Yeah?
I don't know.
Not so much, maybe.
But maybe when
you are the boss,
you will just keep
your feet up and relax.
Mm.
The real important thing--
And not everyone
knows this.
--is to be tough.
Boss has to be tough.
Has to say no to people.
Has to make cashiers
wipe down cars,
even if they don't want to.
Can you be tough, Walter?
I am sure you can handle.
And if not, you can always
call your wife, no?
Always sticky.
Yeah.
No problem.
As is.
Who'd have thought
that someday l would be
handing these keys to you?
Many years. Almost forgot.
Bogdan.
As is.
♪ Exactly everything ♪
Thank you.
Mm-hm.
♪ But l can't believe ♪
♪ She gives it all to me ♪
♪ Arms that reach ♪
♪ To hold me tenderly ♪
You okay there?
I'm fine.
Just not using is...
♪ She gives it all to me ♪
♪ She gives me more ♪
Eat something.
♪ Than any one man deserves ♪
♪ l who have everything ♪
♪ Am nothing without her ♪
♪ Somehow she knows ♪
♪ l need her desperately ♪
♪ She gives it all to me ♪♪
Yeah?
That's right,
both of them.
All right.
I'm on my way.
You need any help?
No.
You want me to call her back?
No. No.
What exactly did she say?
I mean, exactly.
Just, you know, she asked
if l was okay and not to worry.
Like that.
Hm. Any rough timetable
on this thing, as to when
she's coming home?
It's about
the gambling, right?
Well, it's kind of hard to--
Dad, she can't understand.
It's not like you're doing this
on purpose. You can't help it.
It's not
that simple.
Look, you have a disease.
It's like you're an alcoholic, right?
No, it's not. Not at all.
Yes, it is. l read online.
She's not even allowed
to be mad at you.
She can't be mad at you
about the cancer, can she?
Son, these are two
very different things.
Not really.
Gambling addiction is a sickness.
You can't--
Listen, what is going on with me
is not about some disease.
It's about choices.
Choices that I have made.
Choices I stand by.
You're not moving
back in, are you?
No.
Hey, you know what?
School can wait.
Why don't we take
a little detour?
What kind of detour?
You'll see.
- Charlie, pick up line three.
- Line three, Charlie.
I think it's time
we got you your own car.
What do you think?
What?
I think if you're gonna
buy me off,
buy me off.
Get an attendant over to the lot.
♪ Make songs that monarchs know ♪
♪ Ti-ti-ti-la-so-fa
Mi-mi-mi-mi-re-do ♪
♪ Call me Aloe Blacc
'Cause I need that dollar, yo, ha, ha ♪
♪ Hic-hic-hiccup
Blame it on the liquor ♪
♪ l came through like a stickup
Now I'm ballin' like a kick up ♪♪
Wow.
Amazing. It's amazing.
Yeah. It's good-looking.
That's good.
I'm glad you like it.
I do. Thank you, Dad.
All right. You're welcome.
So you're here.
Yeah.
You're actually here?
To work?
Yeah, man. Jesus.
Jesse.
Come here.
- All right, I need an update.
- Update on what?
An update on these little
field trips that you've
been taking with Mike.
I told you already.
We pick up money.
Check on things.
Stuff like that.
And you're his bodyguard, right?
What? That's what you said.
I said l guarded him.
Like backup,
like a second set of eyes.
Everybody needs
backup, right?
And this has to be you?
It can't be, I don't know,
Tyrus or any of the couple
dozen muscle-heads
that Gus has
working for him?
It has to be Jesse Pinkman.
Why? What, is there something
about you that I don't know?
Are you a former
Navy SEAL?
Your hands registered
as lethal weapons?
Register this.
All l'm saying is that
do you not even question this?
Do you really believe that you
mean anything to these people?
Not trying to insult.
Just trying to make
you see things.
I see they can't outright
kill me, but they don't
want me getting high.
I see this thing probably
started as Gus getting
Mike to babysit me.
But you know what?
I saved Mike from getting robbed,
even killed, maybe.
So maybe I'm not
such a loser after all.
I mean, what if it--? Oh, God.
All right. What if it's all just a setup?
What?
What if this robbery that
you stopped wasn't even real?
I mean, think about it.
Your first day out guarding Mike.
He steps out for one second
and what happens?
You immediately get robbed.
You are such an asshole.
Keep your friends close,
your enemies closer.
Like you said,
Gus can't kill you because of me,
he knows l won't stand for it.
He hates the fact
that he needs me.
What does he do? He goes to work
driving a wedge between you and me.
If you'd been there,
you'd know it wasn't a setup.
Wait a minute. How long
did those guys chase you, huh?
Because the way you describe it,
they gave up pretty damn easy.
No, no, this whole thing,
all of this...
it's all about me.
Hello?
Uh, look, just hang on.
Yeah?
I'll be right up.
What?
I gotta go.
What? Am I supposed
to clean all this on my own?
Hey.
God--
Ah!
Buenos dias, ladies, buenos dias.
Do you speak English?
No.
No, okay. Um...
Ah! Help, help. Uh...
I need help to clean.
Yes.
Yes, muy bueno. It's just this--
No.
No, no, no.
No, no, ladies.
Let me see, let me see.
I tell you what. I tell
you what. Look, look.
Universal language.
This one for you.
Yeah, sí.
Sí, Presidente Grant.
Very important man.
Mas dinero after the--
Are we good?
I think we're good.
I think we listened to you.
Please, por favor, por favor.
Ah! Yes.
What's the deal?
Well, the deal is,
we're watching that house.
Couple down on the left
with the tree in the front.
Yeah? What for?
A little birdie told me
there's some guys
that have 3 pounds of our product
which they're selling.
And which they sure as hell
didn't get from us.
So, what's the plan?
I just told you.
We sit here and watch that house
until one of our entrepreneurs
pops his head out.
Then we ask a few questions
and get our property back.
Why don't you just go
break the door down,
pistol-whip those bitches
and show them who's boss?
Because a little birdie
also told me these guys
are into the product
and most likely armed.
Now, what you may not
know about meth-heads--
Or maybe you do.
They're kind of
unpredictable.
I don't care for unpredictable.
So we wait.
Sorry to burst your bubble, kid,
but that's 90 percent of the job.
Don't worry.
I brought sandwiches.
Yes, sir. Heh.
Uh...
Pimento cheese.
How's that sound?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where you going?
You said they're selling right?
Maybe I'm looking to buy.
Who the hell are you?
- Tucker! Tucker!
- I'm here to buy.
- Will you shut the damn door?
- Not my question.
Name's Diesel. Heard you
maybe had some of the blue.
Tucker. Shut the door, Tucker!
- I just-- Just looking for a teenth, yo.
- Tucker! Tucker!
- Come on, help a brother out.
- Tucker!
Will you shut the damn door?
We don't sell to strangers.
- Tucker!
- Get off the porch, asshole.
Will you shut the door?
All right already!
Tucker!
Guess we'll go with
Plan A, then.
Pop the trunk, would you?
Why?
There's something in there l need.
And what would that be?
I'm getting those pricks
out of that house.
Oh, your first attempt being
such a wild success?
You may know this whole
PI sit-in-the-car business,
but l know meth-heads.
What are you doing?
Digging.
Why?
You know why.
How deep are you going?
I don't know.
How deep do you think it is?
Pretty deep.
Hey, uh, you mind taking over
for a minute?
Yeah, sure.
Hey, uh, mind if l use your john?
Yeah.
Tucker.
Tucker!
Who the hell are you?
I just--
It's cool.
Hey, I'm a friend of Tucker's.
What do you want?
I just wanna buy some of the blue.
It's not for sale.
I know you were selling it earlier--
Oh, yeah?
How do you know that?
Uh, Tucker told me.
Yeah, Tucker needs to learn
to keep his damn mouth shut.
Tucker! Tucker!
So, uh, you gonna hook me up?
Don't have enough for all
of Tucker's asshole friends. Tucker!
You know, I think he's outside.
You wanna just go outside--
Tucker! Tucker!
Hey, hey. Let's go find Tucker.
Okay? Let's go outside.
I don't have enough
for you, all right?
Yeah. yeah. Yeah, l get it. Okay.
I don't wanna start any trouble.
Trouble? What's that mean? Trouble?
No, no, no.
I'm just saying we're cool, okay?
We're good.
What?
You can't know that.
What does that mean?
You don't put thoughts
in my head.
You don't put thoughts in my head.
Absolutely. You're right. You're right.
Tucker?
You--
Here you go, Maria.
Veronica.
Ilia, gracias.
I missed that one.
I'm sure it was good.
Wait, where you taking them?
Come on, Tyrus, what are you doing?
I'm putting them on a bus.
Why? What bus?
One that takes them back to Honduras.
Hey, wait a second. Wait a minute.
Wait, wait. This was my idea.
Don't punish them.
You tell Gus to blame me,
not them.
He does.
♪ But I'm not different
I'm just me ♪
♪ And that's the only way
That l know how to be ♪
Give us a minute, will you?
♪ You know, I ain't never
Asked for a lot ♪
♪ And that's about all
That l ever got ♪
♪ But there's one thing
That l sure would like to see ♪
We won't be too long.
♪ When l cash in my final chip ♪
♪ And they lay me down
For my last trip ♪♪
The crew that hit our truck
gave away the cargo
to a couple
local nobodies.
Very disciplined of them,
not keeping anything
for themselves.
It was all about
sending a message.
Which they did, literally.
It was written on the bucket lid.
"Ready to talk?"
That, I believe,
is the English translation.
I know you're not really asking
for advice.
But let me hire 1 0, 1 5 more
good operators.
Then we hit them hard.
Hit them where they live.
No. This war stays cold for now.
What about their message?
What's the answer?
Set up a meeting.
Let's see what they have to say.
How did he do today?
I hear you can
handle yourself.
I guess.
Good night.
Hey, excuse me?
Why me?
I like to think
I see things in people.
Slow down. The car
is not going anywhere.
Mom.
Hey, sweetheart.
Hi.
Hey.
Whew.
So did you see what's in the driveway?
There you go.
Uh, yeah, l saw.
Hey.
So that's yours, huh?
Yeah.
Dad got it for me.
Well, that was
very nice of him.
Yeah. Heh.
I know it looks like...
well, awesome, but it's super safe.
Dad made sure.
And I promise to always go
the speed limit. Or below.
Way below.
And it gets great gas mileage.
So Dad said l can take it around
the block a few times. That okay?
Just around the block.
Yeah. Just around
the block.
And be careful, okay?
I will.
Bye.
It's really-- lt's really great
to have you home, Mom.
Hey, seriously,
be careful. Okay?
I will.
Okay.
I guess we should talk.
Well, I think you said
plenty the other day.
Look, about that, it just...
Did you get
the car wash keys?
Um, yes. Yes. Here.
Skyler, I may have
overstated things earlier
and I'm sorry
to be so forward.
But l just-- l want you
to know something.
I want you to--
I need you to understand
that you are safe.
You, Junior, Holly.
You are completely safe.
Everything that l do,
everything,
I do it to protect this family.
So buying that car,
that was protecting your family?
Okay. I...
All right, maybe
it's a little flashy,
but he needed a car,
and I'm his father,
and I should be able
to get what he wants.
It goes back.
Tomorrow.
Skyler, it will crush him.
That car directly
contradicts our story.
And if you're so invested
in protecting this family,
it means protecting the story.
What do you think the neighbors
are gonna say, Walt?
What about Hank and Marie?
How about the IRS?
What were you thinking, Walt?
I was thinking that l wanted
to do something nice for my son.
Look.
I just worry that
he'll blame you for this.
Oh, he will.
Once again,
he'll blame his bitch mother
for taking away what his
loving father has given him,
so thanks for that.
But you know what, Walt?
Someone has to protect
this family
from the man
who protects this family.