More.
Another.
Careful, señor.
Hot day like today...
...too much oil in the machine...
...can cause it to blow a gasket.
There are two kinds of men
in this world.
Those who drink...
...and those who pour.
Shut up and fill my glass.
Hey, you two.
Yes, you.
I used to be just like you.
Worked dirt for the man
till my hands bled.
But no more.
Because I learned that a man
can never drink his fill...
...by waiting in line for the tap.
Listen to him.
He can teach you something!
Hey, how you doing, boss?
Good to see you, my friend.
You know, I never pegged you
for such a deep thinker.
I keep thinking I should write a book.
Maybe, maybe...
So, what brings you to this
burro's asshole of a town?
I knew I would find you here.
Don't you have something to deliver?
Cutting it close, aren't you?
Lots of time.
Tortuga may be slow out of the gate,
but he always...
Finishes first.
Yes, I know.
Just like your namesake.
I like the way you talk, Tortuga.
Yeah?
You've got such a way with words.
They flow like a waterfall.
I like that about you.
I'm so stupid.
I missed your birthday.
No, I feel terrible.
So bad I came all the way here
to this burro's asshole...
...to give you your present.
Present?
Come on, boss.
No need to go through the trouble.
Forget it, I wanted to.
I have it for you in the back.
- Back there?
- Yes. Come. Follow me.
It's perfect!
Do you really like it?
I love it!
What a great pet it will make.
Thank you, boss!
Excellent.
Let me sign it for you.
Let me sign it...
..."For the big talker."
He's still breathing.
Well, by the looks of him,
he has no idea how close he came.
I'm assuming Saul Goodman
doesn't need to know.
Mum's the word.
Son of a bitch.
Hang on, baby.
Hello.
Walt? Are you in the house?
Oh, hey, Skyler. Yeah, it's me.
What? What the hell
are you doing in there?
I'm back.
No, no, you're not back, Walt.
You're not back.
Get... Get out of there.
- Well, it's my house too, Skyler.
- No...
I'm staying. End of story.
- We had an agreement.
- I didn't agree to anything.
Now, look, just come on inside
and we'll talk this through, okay?
No. No. There's nothing to talk about.
I am not coming in there
until you get out.
Well, suit yourself.
Walt.
Walt?
What is wrong with you?
- Skyler, I have every right to be here.
- No, you don't.
You don't live here anymore.
We're getting a divorce.
- I don't agree to a divorce.
- Well, it's not up to you.
If you don't get out of here right now,
I'm gonna call the police...
...and I'm going to tell them
everything.
I mean it, Walt.
There's the phone.
It's ringing.
Albuquerque Police Department.
Operator number 314.
How may I help you?
Albuquerque Police Department.
Yes, I want to report a disturbance,
please.
No, no, it's not...
It's not exactly, it's...
It's a domestic issue.
Okay.
They're connecting me.
Right hand to God, I will tell them.
Do what you have to do, Skyler.
This family is everything to me.
- Without it, I have nothing to lose.
- Fine.
Yes. My name is Skyler White.
I need police assistance
at my home right away.
My soon-to-be-ex-husband
broke into my house...
...and I need an officer to come
and remove him.
It's 308 Negra Arroyo Lane.
Okay. Okay.
Thank you.
They're coming.
- Dad's here?
- Great, he's home.
- Dad.
- Hey, son.
How are you?
Are you back for good?
- Why are you home so soon?
- I'm not.
Hey, I am starving.
How about a grilled cheese?
- Sure.
- You want one too?
Walter, your dad and I
have something we need to discuss.
When your sandwich is ready,
I'll bring it to your room.
Mom, can't it wait?
I haven't seen Dad in, like, forever.
- Walter?
- How was school?
- It was good.
- Yeah? Homework?
- No, not really.
- Not really? What does that mean?
So are you gonna be
at work tomorrow?
Yeah, that's the plan.
Hello, ma'am.
We were called about a disturbance?
It's more of a trespassing situation,
really, but...
Yeah, that was me.
You called the cops on Dad?
I came home from work
and he was back.
He had just moved back
into the house.
And I asked him to leave,
but he won't listen. I just...
I want him out.
I want him out of the house.
Okay, Mrs. White, there's a couple
questions I need to ask you.
It's very important
you answer honestly.
- Did he strike you?
- No.
- Has he ever hit you?
- No. This is not about violence.
This is about trespassing.
- About him being here against my will.
- Okay. Trespassing.
- You're divorced, then?
- No, working on it.
- Right now, were separated.
- Legally separated?
There's not a court order,
if that's what you mean.
But we've been living apart
for almost two weeks, give or take.
I changed the locks.
Isn't that breaking and entering?
Whose name is on the title
to the house?
Both of us. It's jointly owned.
We can't arrest a man for breaking
into his own house.
Not without a court order
requiring he stays away.
Unless he's threatened you
or the kids.
No. Not physically.
But having him in the house is just...
It's not a good thing. Excuse me.
I got her, honey.
Come here. Here we go.
You hungry? You hungry?
Here we go.
That was it.
- I'm sorry, officer. Where were we?
- Disagreements.
Yes, well,
we've had our share of that.
I haven't... I haven't been
the most attentive husband lately.
Mrs. White, would this be easier
if we stepped outside for a minute?
No. Nope. I'm fine right here.
I'm gonna level with you, ma'am.
If you want him out of the house,
you'll have to help me.
Is it possible maybe he's broken
any laws that you know of?
Anything at all. Anything that
we could work with here, just tell me.
Even if it's just a suspicion,
I can work with that.
I'll get him out of the house for you.
What's your take on all this?
It's my mom's fault.
She won't even say what my dad did
and it's because he didn't do anything.
I don't know why
she's being this way.
My dad, he is a great guy.
Son, it's not your mom's fault.
Mrs. White.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
There's no legal basis...
...for us to remove your husband
from the house.
Next time you feel things
are getting out of control...
...you should call this number.
It's the family hotline.
I'd really look into
some counseling.
Best of luck to you folks.
Listen, thank you, officers.
We're sorry.
Why you gotta...?
Why you gotta do this to Dad?
Junior, wait, come on.
Don't blame your mother for this.
Sorry.
Welcome home.
He lives. Happy housewarming, kid.
- Don't look so glad to see me.
- Thanks.
Interesting decor. It's subtle.
The whole minimalist thing never
really blew my hair back, but hey.
So how are you doing?
Staying clean?
Good. I was kind of worried
that you were back to old habits...
...since I didn't hear from you,
you know.
You realize how stupid it is
to ignore your counsel's phone calls?
What if I was trying to warn you...
...that the DEA was gonna kick down
your door? What then?
Why don't you spare me the sermon
and get to why you're here?
Fair enough.
Remember the other day...
...when I brought up the idea of you
getting back in touch with your partner?
Well, I kind of wanted to
re-float that boat.
I'm not suggesting you
yourself get back to cooking.
I mean, you being in rehab and all.
I only want you to convince
the master chef to do his thing.
So, what do you say?
- Sure, man. Whatever.
- Okay. Whatever what?
I mean, you gonna call him?
I said I'll handle it.
Now, bounce, will you? Please?
Final thought.
Look at this place. You're house-poor,
you got no bankroll.
If you get the maestro cooking again,
I'll make it worth your while.
Call him.
If you're trying to sell me something,
I've got four words for you:
"Do Not Call list."
However, if you're cool,
leave it at the beep.
Schrader.
Yes, sir. Yeah, what's up?
Yeah?
That's great news, sir. Thank you.
Yeah, yeah, absolutely,
you can bet on that.
Hey, listen, thanks again, sir...
...I really appreciate you stepping
to the plate. Thank you.
So you gonna keep me in suspense
or what? What's the good news?
Merkert called in a couple of favors.
El Paso wants me back.
Hey, man, congrats, man.
That's fantastic.
Thank you.
Hello.
Gentlemen. Welcome.
Thank you for coming.
Any difficulty at the border?
The day I can't get across the border
is the day I retire.
Please, come in.
I apologize that it's not
wheelchair accessible.
My apologies, Gustavo.
Of course,
you should have been advised.
It's your territory,
you had a right to bless the order.
But...
We had no reason to believe
the man was of concern to you.
Indeed, he is.
So you're in business with
this Heisenberg.
I don't know him by that name,
but yes.
I've made no secret of the fact that...
...I have always done business
with certain local manufacturers.
You and I,
we still make money together.
It's never affected our relationship.
Don Salamanca had
a nephew named Tuco.
Yes, I knew of him.
Then perhaps you know Salamanca
mentored him in the business.
Thought of Tuco as a son.
When Don Salamanca was no longer
able, Tuco took over for his uncle.
He was a key man in our
organization north of the border.
He was loyal.
This Heisenberg, Walter White...
...he was one of
Tuco's local suppliers.
Until he betrayed Tuco.
So now you see,
blood must be repaid by blood.
Tuco's cousins here...
...they have the right
to exact vengeance.
The Salamanca family, the cartel...
...everyone stands shoulder
to shoulder on this.
Don Salamanca.
Gentlemen.
I feel your loss deeply.
Please accept my condolences.
I have no issue with
your right to vengeance.
But I am presently engaged in
business with this man.
When our business is done...
...he will no longer be
of any concern to me.
Until then...
...I need him alive.
Excuse us.
I don't tell you how to
fry your chickens, Gustavo.
You should really leave matters
of my organization's politics to me.
Do I not run my own territory?
Of course you do.
And I will advise them to be patient.
But I recommend you finish your
business with the man quickly.
Or you risk losing
the good graces of the cartel.
That would not be wise.
And those boys inside...
...I cannot guarantee
that they will listen.
They are not like you and I.
If you're trying to sell me something,
I've got four words for you:
"Do Not Call list."
However, if you're cool,
leave it at the beep.
If you're trying to sell me something,
I've got four words for you:
"Do Not Call list."
However, if you're cool,
leave it at the beep.
If you're trying to sell me something,
I've got four words for you...
Sweetheart. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's okay. It's okay, my girl.
Yes, it's okay. It's okay.
Mama's got you.
I've got you. Yes. Yes.
Skyler? Want some help?
Skyler, can I use the bathroom?
God...
- What do you mean? Against your will?
- Yes.
Very much against my will.
He just... He showed right back up.
And he doesn't want a divorce.
Won't even consider it.
I called the police on him.
I was so clo...
- So close to what?
- Nothing. Never mind.
Skyler, I can't advise you properly
if you don't give me all the facts.
Understand, I'm bound
by the attorney-client privilege...
...to keep everything you tell me
a secret.
I can't tell a soul
unless you authorize me to.
Even if it's something illegal?
Especially if it's illegal.
I'm your lawyer, not the police.
My job is to protect you.
My husband makes meth.
Methamphetamine.
- Your husband's a drug dealer?
- A manufacturer, technically.
They... They call them cooks.
I looked it up on the Internet.
This is my advice,
and you should take it:
Sue your husband for divorce
immediately.
Let me go to the police
and tell them what you just told me.
I'll go in ex parte to get a
restraining order from the court today.
If he comes anywhere near you and
your children, he'll go straight to jail.
No questions asked.
This is a no-brainer.
It's the best thing for you
and your family.
I can't.
I can't do it.
I don't want my son to find out
that his father is a criminal.
I just...
- I can't do that to him.
- In the end, it may not be up to you.
Drug dealers have a way
of getting caught.
Walt has lung cancer.
His treatment bought him some time.
But the doctors,
they all say that sooner or later...
I can't see why
I should lay all this on my family...
...when things may...
...resolve themselves on their own...
...without anyone else knowing.
Man, did I lose a bet or something?
- What are we doing in this shithole?
- Relax, will you?
Relax? This is the kind of place
you get knifed.
- We should have went to Chili's, man.
- All right, already. Jesus.
Outback Steakhouse. It's not too late.
They got that Blooming Onion.
What's wrong with spicing things
up a little?
This spice looks like it's been through
a couple of guys already.
So when you headed back down
to El Paso?
You know. Between all the packing,
errands, getting the ducks in a row...
...maybe a week or two.
- Week or two?
Come on, man.
I'd be dying to get back in the action.
It's not like
there's nothing going on up here.
What are you talking about?
Ain't jack going on up here.
It's quiet as hell.
I'm gonna hit the head.
Those two over there.
I think they're holding.
Man, in this place,
the bartender's probably holding.
- All right.
- What you doing?
Calling A.P.D., what do you think?
Since when can't we handle
a couple dirtballs?
Come on, man. Courtesy call.
What if Vice is running
some kind of undercover op?
Screw it. It's your turn to pay.
- Where you going?
- Gotta take a leak.
Jesus, get yourself some Flomax.
Stand up.
You got a problem with us, bitch?
Your move.
DEA. Don't move.
Go out and tell my partner
to get his ass in here.
If you're trying to sell me something,
I've got four words for you:
"Do Not Call list."
However, if you're cool,
leave it at the beep.
If you're trying to sell me something,
I've got four words for you:
"Do Not Call..."
The number you have reached,
149-4985...
...in area code 505 is no longer...
Skyler.
Can we talk?
ASAC wants to see you.
And?
We were hanging back,
saw a deal go down.
I went outside to call it in.
You stayed to keep an eye
on the suspects.
That's when they attacked you.
What I didn't tell him is that
you left your gun under the seat...
...before you went back inside.
I've done a terrible thing.
But I did it for a good reason.
I did it for us.
That is college tuition
for Walter Jr...
...and Holly 18 years
down the road.
That is health insurance
for you and the kids.
For Junior's physical therapy,
his SAT tutor.
It's money for groceries...
...for gas...
...for birthdays
and graduation parties.
Skyler, that money is for this roof
over your head...
...the mortgage you aren't
gonna be able to afford...
...on a part-time bookkeeper's salary
when I'm gone.
- Walt, I...
- Please. Please.
This money, I didn't steal it.
It doesn't belong to anyone else.
I earned it.
The things I've done to earn it...
...the things that I've had to do...
...I've got to live with them.
Skyler...
...all that I've done...
...all the sacrifices that I have
made for this family...
...all of it will be for nothing
if you don't accept what I've earned.
Please.
I'll be here
when you get home from work.
You can give me your answer then.
Hey, Sky.
- Hey, some coffee?
- Yeah.
That report's looking real good.
I like how it looks.
Good.
Are your kids home?
It's here! It's here!
Everybody, come on in! Look!
Hey, Mrs. White.
Hey, Louis.
Hey, thanks for having me
over for dinner.
Sure.
Hey, Skyler. I'm cooking dinner.
Pot roast. Could you?
So how was your day?
- Good.
Excellent.
I hope you don't mind, I invited Louis
to stay for dinner tonight.
You know, as a thank-you for driving
Walter Jr. To school for us.
We've been kind of absent...
...but, I tell you,
Louis really pitched in.
Look, I just wanna say that I feel good
about our talk this morning...
...and I'm very eager
to hear what you're thinking about...
...about what we talked about.
But, you know,
whenever you're ready, of course.
Honesty is good. Don't you think?
I fucked Ted.
Boys, dinner.
- Iced tea?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Louis?
- Yes, please.
All right.
I want you boys both
to eat your salad, okay?
- Okay.
- I know nobody likes salad...
...but it's good for you.
- Thanks, darling.
- Thank you.