Here is, uh... Here's my résumé.
I mean, technically it says
"curriculum vitae,"
which I think is more
professional, but, you know,
same thing, pretty much.
That's... Wow, great.
This position truly is a
no-experience-necessary kind of thing.
Well, and it doesn't
really say it here,
but I have a solid
background in sales.
I'm pretty much a self-starter, so...
That's excellent, but...
Excellent.
I just... I really feel I could
be a major,
major asset to your sales force.
Ah.
I'm thinking there's
a little misunderstanding.
This isn't actually
a sales job.
I mean, I'd be happy to consider
you for a sales position,
but all our agents
need to be licensed,
have at least two years
on-the-job experience
and usually
a college degree.
Oh.
What you'll be doing
is more like
advertising.
Hey, Jesse.
Hey, man.
Yo, man.
What up?
Badger?
Where you been
keeping yourself?
Nice duds.
Yeah,
you too.
Thanks.
Yo, why would you wanna
do this lame-ass job, anyway?
I mean, no offense.
Because I'm on
probation, yo.
I gotta prove to the man
I'm rehabilitated.
Upstanding citizen,
all that shit.
It's really good
exercise too. Look.
You can't just stand there,
you have to spin the arrow.
There's all these moves you have
to learn, like "the helicopter."
Wow.
Yeah. See, yeah?
That one's a bitch.
I'm not very good
at it yet.
Well, you really opened
my eyes to the possibilities.
Yeah.
Hey, anyways,
thanks for the toke.
Any time.
Speaking of which,
you think you could maybe
hook me up with some crystal?
Ah, no, I've been out of
the business for a while.
Actually, now thinking
about retiring.
What? No.
Yeah.
That stuff you made
is unbelievable.
It was pretty awesome.
Retirement?
Ah! I can't be hearing this.
No, man, I had this partner
who was helping me cook.
I mean, I was doing
most of the work...
but he was an asshole, so...
Anyway, I mean, pseudo's getting
harder and harder to come by and...
Yo, I can hook you up
with some pseudo.
Major pseudo.
I got channels, bro.
We could partner up.
Huh?
No pressure.
No pressure. Just think
about it, all right?
Oh, shit. I gotta go.
Yo, this way to savings.
Save your dollar bills, y'all.
♪ This way to savings
This way to savings ♪
Come on!
Save some money.
It's a stupid gift.
No, it isn't. He'll love it.
I don't know
what I was thinking.
Didn't the invitation
even say "no gifts"?
Walt.
What?
We have to go.
I know, I'm not complaining.
Yes, you are.
Look, we need this.
We've been through
a lot lately. Okay?
Jesus, guess we
didn't get the "beige" memo.
Ah, we're okay.
Yes, I look like I'm wearing
a prom dress from 1985.
Honey, you look fine.
Walt, this is the only thing
I could find that fit me.
God, would you look at that.
The invitation said "no gifts."
So? Come on.
Sir, I'll take that
for you.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Ahem. Oh, look,
there's Elliott.
Oh, come on,
let's go say hello.
Elliott. Ha.
Walt. You made it.
Happy birthday.
Wouldn't miss it for the world.
Thank you. Skyler.
Hi. Oh. Oh, that's right.
Great to see you. You look
beautiful, as always.
Oh. Well, these days a little
more big than beautiful, but...
Of course, congratulations.
That was such great news.
Thank you.
Gretchen, look who's here.
- Oh.
Oh, it's been ages.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Oh, it's really good.
Heh-heh.
Skyler, welcome.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
It's really nice to be here.
- When are you due?
- In about 10 more weeks.
And actually, we recently
found out that it's a girl.
Oh, that's so wonderful.
Yeah.
Yeah, we've been thinking
about it for ourselves.
Yeah, thinking about it.
Uh, oh, hey, by the way,
securing that patent
was just amazing.
I mean, the work that
your company is doing...
Congratulations
to both of you.
Hard work and a lot of luck. A lot.
Yeah. Oh, well, now.
Elliott.
Uh, will you excuse us?
We gotta say hi.
Make yourselves at home,
we'll catch up later.
Sure, sure. Okay.
Okay.
So glad you're here.
Thank you.
Bye.
John, Missy. How are you?
Shall we?
Congratulations.
Happy birthday.
Oh.
Wow.
Hm. Hm.
Walt?
I thought
that was you.
Farley.
Long time no see.
This is Walter White.
Oh. Hello.
Back at Caltech,
he was...
You were just a master
of crystallography.
I remember
this one time
we were stuck on this
protein problem for weeks.
You just breezed
right in,
and you had
one word for us...
Synchrotrons.
Mm.
It was synchrotrons,
yeah.
They generate pure
and more complete
patterns than x-ray beams.
Data collection takes
a fraction of the time.
This is the White
in Gray Matter.
Tell them, Walt.
Okay.
Well, back when Elliott and I
were in grad school,
we came up with
the name. Ahem.
Schwartz, black.
Walter White.
So together they became
Gray Matter Technologies.
Cute, huh?
So you run the company with Elliott?
No. No, that's
Gretchen and Elliott.
Yeah, yeah. You know,
I gravitated toward education.
Ah. What university?
Oh, wow,
it's a Stratocaster.
Not just any Strat.
That's one of Clapton's.
No way.
"To Elliott, sorry about the
buckle rash, Eric Clapton."
Thank you.
This is beautiful.
- Why is he doing this?
- Beautiful.
What is he, like 8 years old?
Here, honey.
Thanks.
Oh, this is from Walt.
Oh, God.
It's okay.
Hey.
Let's see what we got.
Yum Good Ramen.
This is what Walt
and I lived on
for, uh, 10 months straight
while we were working
on our thesis.
Sold them down at Ralstow's
in the hardware aisle.
Right next to the...
What was it?
- Sterno. Yeah.
- The Sterno.
Yeah, 10 for
a dollar ninety-nine.
To this day, I am convinced
these noodles
were responsible
for our success.
This was our lifeblood.
Man, where'd you find these? I thought
they'd been outlawed years ago.
I love it.
Thank you, Walt.
Well...
For the man
who has everything.
- No, no, no.
- It was.
No, you remember the fat guy.
Yes.
We used to call him Snot Trough.
He had that thing
under his nose.
What do you call that thing?
That was Dobkins.
That was the same guy who always
smelled like chocolate milk.
It was.
No, no, no.
It wasn't Dobkins,
it was...
Anyway, I swear to Christ,
he used to iron those patches
onto the elbows of his
Members Only jacket
because he thought it made him
look more distinguished.
Didn't it? I thought it...
No.
Oh, God.
Well, here's to Snot Trough.
To Snot Trough.
Wherever you may be.
God bless him.
And you remember the professor who
used to hate Robert Wilhelm Bunsen?
Yes. All you had to do was
mention the Bunsen burner
and he was off on a rant.
"Oh, he didn't invent it."
Do you remember the waving?
"He just improved it,"
you know.
It was easy to kill
15 minutes.
Yeah.
Oh, God.
I miss this, Walt.
Yeah. Me too.
Listen, we ought to get
together more often.
Skyler and I would love to have you and
Gretchen over for dinner sometime.
Oh, sure, yeah,
absolutely.
But, you know, what I mean is that you
and I should work together again.
Are you gonna teach high school?
No, no, no, seriously.
What's stopping us?
Wait a minute, Elliott,
what are you...?
Are you asking me to come
work for you at Gray Matter?
Yeah, why not?
You'd fit right in.
You're brilliant,
you got a ton of experience.
Well, I...
I wouldn't really know
where to begin. I mean...
God, you have no idea.
I spend my days just drawing
out atoms on the chalkboard
and trying to get these kids
to learn the periodic table.
Look, I understand.
You're a little rusty, but you're
not seeing the upside here.
We could really benefit
from a new set of eyes.
You know what it's like when you've
been trying to crack some problem
for months on end,
you get tunnel vision.
One guy thinking outside of the box,
you may be exactly what we need.
Well, listen, Elliott, it...
The offer is very appealing,
it really is, I thank you.
But there's...
There's something
you should know.
I have some personal issues.
Look, there's nothing
we can't work out.
Well, yeah,
but it's complicated.
We can help you.
We have excellent
health insurance.
The best.
Ahem. Um, hey, did you try
those prosciutto-wrapped figs?
They were, like, wow.
They were just...
I must have had about
30 of those suckers.
Oh, and the seafood table,
did you see that?
They had lobster tail, they
had crab legs, like, shrimp.
They had...
Walt.
What the hell did you say to Elliott?
What?
You told him about the cancer,
didn't you? Didn't you?
I can't believe it.
Okay, we were talking, he
asked how you were doing,
and I am sorry, but I don't have the best
poker face these days where that's concerned.
He knew something was wrong
with you, and he pressed me.
He pressed you? Come on.
Walt, when it came
right down to it,
I didn't know what else to do
but tell him the truth.
The truth? Well, how about
you just said, "He's fine," huh?
You think maybe you could just have said that?
"He's fine." And then it would have been done.
I don't like the way
you're talking to me.
I don't like the way you talk
about my private affairs
to people who are not
even in our lives anymore.
Well, what exactly
did he say to you?
He offered me a job.
What?
Yes. Kind of like some
fig leaf, you know.
Some face-saving
bullshit
that allowed me to generously
accept his charity.
And then when I turned
that down, he flat out
offered to pay
for my treatment.
Which is exactly what you
expected him to do, didn't you?
Walt.
Didn't you?
No. I did not put him up...
Please. Come on. Come on.
Okay, what did you say?
Walt?
What do you think I said?
Why? Walt.
Hm. Ready to go?
I'm taking the bus.
Okay.
Bye, honey.
Hey, dude.
Are these bullet holes?
Uh...
No, man. Those are for,
like, you know,
uh, ventilation.
Cool.
Ooh. Nice setup, huh?
Man.
This is nothing, man.
I used to have, like,
twice as much glassware,
until my dumb-ass
ex-partner
drove us into a ditch
and wrecked most of it.
Big-ass beaker, huh?
Hey, wait, wait, no, that's...
Yeah, that's a boiling flask.
This is a beaker.
Here's a Griffin beaker.
Here's a volumetric beaker.
Here's an Erlenmeyer flask.
Um, you got...
Wow. You really
know your shit.
It's just basic chemistry, yo.
So...
you got something for me?
Aw, hells, yeah.
Okay. We're in business.
Right on, Badger.
Dude, check
this out.
Jesus.
What the hell are you
bringing that for?
Hunting.
We might see javelinas.
Are you gonna help me
or what?
Hey.
Badger!
Huh? Huh? Yeah?
Yeah, buddy. Huh? Yeah.
Let's see the money.
Here.
I need five each.
Come on, two more.
Here.
What about him?
Are you kidding?
He looks younger than us.
Whatever.
What about
that guy?
No, he looks like
a businessman.
So what?
So businessmen
are always in a hurry.
They're always, like, going
to some meeting or something.
Seriously, he's just
gonna say no.
Hey, hey, this guy.
This is our guy.
You're up.
Huh? Why do I
have to do it?
Give me the crutches
and I'll go do it.
Shit.
Um, excuse me, hey,
we forgot our IDs,
and we were wondering
if you could do us a favor
and buy us a six-pack?
You know, what you're
asking is illegal.
Um, no, it's not.
Yeah, it is.
Oh, shit.
Guess you win the jackpot.
This is not how I wanted
to spend my night off.
Consider this your first
and last warning.
Yes, sir.
You're lucky you
got a good dad here.
If the other guys hadn't run,
I could've talked my way out of it.
Not cool, man. Not cool.
What, you never tried to buy
beer when you were my age?
No, I'm talking about you
calling me and not your father.
How do you think
that'd make him feel?
I don't even
know what to say to you.
Just go.
I'll deal with you later.
Phew.
Where's Walt?
I haven't seen him since this morning.
Your guess is as good as mine.
Listen, do me a favor,
all right?
Don't tell him about the kid.
He's just a teenager
trying to score some beer.
You know,
just growing pains.
I mean, he finds out his dad's sick,
he starts acting out, you know?
First the pot,
then this.
The pot?
You told me the kid
was smoking reefer.
That's what Skyler told me.
I mean, you may as well have.
I wasn't talking about Walter, Jr.
I was talking about Walt.
Excuse me?
He admitted it.
He said he liked it.
Walt?
Mm-hm.
Shit.
I didn't think
he had it in him.
It's like he's not himself lately.
Yeah.
I mean,
why would anyone in their right
mind choose not to do treatment?
Especially when
it's completely paid for.
Why is he doing this?
You know what
we need to do?
What we really need to do
is sit him down, all of us,
and get everything out
on the table.
Talk it all through.
You mean an intervention?
No, no.
Just a family meeting.
Where everyone
can voice their concerns
and be heard.
You are a genius, bro.
This cankenstein is unreal.
When we get back, I'm gonna
burn that dollar-bill suit
because we're gonna
make some mad dough.
It's not right.
What do you mean,
it's not right?
It's cloudy. It's not
supposed to be cloudy.
Okay, that last time,
it was glass.
So what? Cloudy, not cloudy?
It looks good enough to me.
Good enough.
Wait, wait.
Yo, what are you doing?
Aah!
Are you out of your mind? I
totally would've smoked that.
Look, it's not for you,
it's for our customers.
They're gonna demand
a certain standard.
What? What...? What are you...?
What?
We'll just do it again.
Until we get it right.
Walt.
Please have a seat and join us.
We can do better.
No, don't you fucking
think about it.
Hey.
Come on.
Three entire pounds
of pseudo wasted.
Do you know how long
I had to spin that stupid sign?
Get off me, psycho.
Helicopter, bitch!
Ah, God!
Asshole.
Open the door.
Come back here,
you bitch!
I'm gonna
mess you up!
This isn't funny!
I really need to understand
your thought process,
because clearly I don't.
I feel that this decision
you've made
is not only
not in your best interest,
it's not in the best interest
of our entire family.
- Look, Skyler...
- Not yet, please. L...
I have the talking pillow.
Everybody gets to speak
their minds, remember?
And then you'll get
your chance.
Money has always been
an issue for us, I'll give you that.
But now that Elliott is more
than willing to pitch in...
Walt, I know, I understand that
it's hard for you to accept help.
Maybe it's the way
you were raised.
But, honey,
it's okay to lean on people
now and again.
You need this treatment.
And nothing can stop you
from getting it,
except you.
- Am I allowed to respond?
- In a minute.
I think we need to go
around the circle first.
Hank, would you
like to start?
Uh, yeah. Okay, well...
What I would say is...
Take the talking pillow.
All right, look, buddy, um,
I know I don't get to
tell you this enough,
but I care about you.
A hell of a lot.
And this cancer thing...
Let's just... Let's face it, you know,
you were dealt a shit hand.
But, um,
sometimes your luck can change.
I mean... I mean, I can't tell
you how many times I was...
You know,
I started with a shit hand
and I ended up with, you know,
a full house. Okay?
I mean, the key is,
you gotta hang in there.
Man, you gotta keep
placing your bets,
keep placing your bets.
Boom.
Hank, what the hell
are you saying?
Please, Marie, let him talk.
That's what we're here
to do. Please.
Go on, Hank.
All right, look at it
this way, okay?
It's the bottom of the ninth,
bases are loaded, you're up.
But you got
a bum arm, right?
There's no fricking way
you're gonna hit a homer, okay?
So you can either let
the pinch hitter take the bat,
or you can hold on to your
pride and lose the game.
You get what
I'm saying?
No.
You got your pride, man.
I get it, okay? I get it.
But this Daddy Warbucks
wants to chip in, man.
I'm with your old lady on this one.
I say take the money and run, man.
Somebody wanna
take this thing? Here.
Yes, Walter...
Walter, Jr., I'm sure
that you have about a million
things to say, probably.
And now is your chance.
Go ahead. Just let it all out.
This is bullshit.
- Hey, come on.
- It's all right.
It...
Talk.
Tell your dad how you feel.
I'm pissed off.
Tell him.
Because you're being...
You're...
You're a pussy.
You're, like,
ready to give up.
You're... God.
What if you gave up
on me, huh?
This here,
all the stuff
I've been through,
and you're scared
of a little chemotherapy?
Me, personally,
I think you should do
whatever you wanna do.
What?
You told us to be honest
about our feelings.
Walt's the one with cancer,
it's his decision.
It's not up to any of us.
Why in hell would you do this?
Hey, hey.
I wasn't planning
on agreeing with Walt.
But after sitting here and listening to you all
talk about his future like he has no say in it...
He's not gonna have a future
if he doesn't get treatment.
I am a medical professional.
I x-ray people in treatment
every day.
I see them every day.
And you know what?
Some of them
are absolutely miserable.
Marie...
I'm sorry, but it's true.
And some of them
don't wanna
spend their last weeks
or months
being picked at by doctors.
But they got talked into it
by their families.
Can I get the pillow back?
I agree with Marie on this one.
- Thank you.
- Hank...
What? Maybe Walt wants
to die like a man, all right?
I don't want him to die at all.
That's the whole point of this.
So either help or leave.
Skyler, I just wanted
to do you the courtesy
of giving you
my honest opinion.
You know, Marie,
this is not debate club.
This is my husband's life
we're talking about here.
You know, I made one
simple observation...
And it's like you...
How dare you...
Okay, so we disagree...
Ladies! Marie!
This is so stupid.
All right, I've got
the talking pillow now.
Okay?
We all, in this room,
we love each other.
We want what's best for
each other, and I know that.
I am very thankful
for that.
But what I want...
What I want,
what I need...
is a choice.
What does that mean?
Sometimes I feel like
I never actually
make any of my own choices,
I mean.
My entire life,
it just seems I never...
you know, had a real say
about any of it.
Now, this last one, cancer,
all I have left is how
I choose to approach this.
Then make the right choice, Walt.
You are not the
only one it affects.
What about your son?
Don't you wanna see your
daughter grow up? I just...
Of course I do.
Skyler, you've read
the statistics, you...
These doctors
talking about "surviving"
one year, two years, like it's
the only thing that matters.
But what good is it
to just survive
if I am too sick to work?
To enjoy a meal?
To make love?
For what time I have left...
I wanna live in my own house.
I wanna sleep in my own bed.
I don't wanna choke down
30 or 40 pills every single day,
and lose my hair,
and lie around,
too tired to get up,
and so nauseated
that I can't even move my head.
And you.
Cleaning up
after me.
And me? What...?
Some, uh...
Some dead man,
some artificially alive...
Just marking time.
No. No.
And that's how you
would remember me.
That's the worst part.
So that is my thought process,
Skyler.
I'm sorry. I just...
I choose not to do it.
All right.
"All right" what?
I'll do the treatment.
It's gonna be okay.
Okay.
The lady from
the billing office
said they usually bill the
insurance company directly.
But since our HMO's not paying for it,
we can pay up front with a credit card.
Oh. Good.
Oh, and then Elliott
will send a check, right?
I will take care of it, yeah.
Walter White?
Yes.
Okay.
- All right.
- Okay.
See you in a minute. Okay.
Okay.
Heh-heh. Elliott.
Walt, it's Gretchen.
Oh, hey. Hey, Gretchen,
how are you?
You know, it was really great seeing
you two the other day, you know.
Wow, what a party.
Walt, Elliott told me
about the cancer.
I'm so sorry.
Well, you know,
it is what it is, I guess.
I don't know what to say.
Except, I'm always here for you.
Both of us are.
We wanted you to know that.
Yeah, well, thank you.
Walt, Elliott told me he'd offered
to pay for the treatment.
You have to accept.
That money, as far as we're both
concerned, that belongs to you.
Even the name of our
company, it's half yours.
Walt?
Is this about you and me?
Gretchen, I really
appreciate the offer.
I do. But we're fine.
As it turns out, the insurance
came through after all.
So, um, I am covered.
And, uh...
Well, and, anyway,
I really appreciate it, I really do.
Thank you.
Good. That's good news.
You know, that really
was a great party.
Keep in touch, okay?
Sure. Sure.
And thank you for calling.
Yo!
Wanna cook?