Just get me home.
I'll do the rest.
Yes, hello, this is David Linn
from The New York Times.
May I speak with Susan,
please? Thank you.
Hi, Susan, it's David again.
I was just calling to see if we can set--
Well, yes. Well, I figured
we'd have to do the interview by phone,
since they've already left New York.
But what we'd really love to get
is a photo of Mr. and Mrs. Schwartz
to go along with the article.
When are they scheduled
to get home?
Oh, so they'll be home
tonight. Gotcha.
Now, the address I have on them
is Upper Canyon Road. Is that still...?
No, it isn't. They've--
Oh, let me get a pen.
Where do they...?
Tesuque. I see.
And the address?
Is that up near the opera house?
I hear that's nice.
Well, I'll be in contact
with my photographer
to check on his schedule.
No, no, it's their call.
I know how busy
Mr. and Mrs. Schwartz are.
Thank you.
This should make one hell of a story.
Goodbye.
I'm just saying,
it's apples and oranges.
Listen, I maintain,
if I want pizza,
I go to a pizza place.
Yeah.
If I want Thai,
I go to a Thai place.
What is the point in comparing
Did I marry you?
pizza to Thai?
What has happened?
- This is different.
- They're completely--
Oh, come on,
are you the man I married?
I am the guy who wants to end
this ridiculous conversation,
kick off my shoes, and have
a very large glass of wine.
Well, I'm gonna tell you
to be my guest.
All right, wait.
The answer is 21.
No.
Yes.
Yes, because it has history.
Come on.
Prohibition.
The Sweet Smell of Success.
And Per Se has Thomas Keller.
Game, set, and match.
The whole vibe is so Yountville.
You transplant it to Manhattan--
Transplant it to Islamabad,
I would eat there.
Oh, there's a good thought.
What, Islamabad?
No, Napa. We have to go to Napa.
Oh, my God, all this talk of food.
Do you think Juana left us anything?
She doesn't think we're coming back
until Wednesday.
Unless you told her.
No, I haven't talked to her.
Oh, look, here.
Just a pear, that'll be perfect.
Yeah.
You wanna get us
a nice bottle of wine?
Mm-hm.
Do you think we have any of those--?
What are those crackers with,
like, the sun-dried tomato,
and they were slightly peppery,
but not too peppery.
- We don't have them?
- No.
Ask Juana.
We haven't had them in forever.
I don't know why she doesn't get those.
Why don't you talk to her?
She's got that thing with her daughter.
Anyway, Napa?
Yeah.
How long since we've been?
Two years.
Jesus, that's two years.
Yeah, too long, right?
Is this okay?
Oh, that looks p e r fe c to.
You wanna get the fireplace?
Is it good?
Mm-hm.
Is it ripe?
Yeah.
We could invite George and Delores.
They could come up from Marin.
And Bill and Miriam Cohen.
We could have a little
spa action, right?
And then we could do
some sort of wine, and then--
Hello, Gretchen.
Elliott.
I really like your new house.
Walt.
This...
Are we looking east?
Oh...
My God, you must have one great view
of the Sangre de Cristos.
Walt,
what are you doing here?
I saw you on Charlie Rose.
You looked great.
You both did.
If you are here to--
To hurt us--
Walt, whatever it is
you're planning--
Actually, I'm here
to give you something.
It's out in my car.
How about the three of us take a walk
to it? It's just parked down the road.
I couldn't get it past your gate.
Elliott, if we're gonna go that way,
you'll need a bigger knife.
Keep stacking. It'll all fit.
That's all right.
Yeah, just throw it on top.
Gretchen, would you mind? We don't
want to lose any under the furniture.
All right.
That is $9,720,000.
Where did it come from?
And why is it here?
I earned it, and you're going to
give it to my children.
What? Why?
Walt, I don't think we--
On my son's 18th birthday,
which is 10 months
and two days from today,
you will give him this money,
in the form of an irrevocable trust.
You will tell him that it is his
to do with as he sees fit,
but with the hope that he uses it
for his college education.
And for the betterment of his family.
Walt, I'm not sure that we follow.
Why...?
I mean, why, in particular,
would we--?
If you wanna give your kids
drug money, go do it yourself.
I can't.
My wife and son hate me.
They won't take my money.
Even if they did,
the federal government
wouldn't let them.
But two rich benefactors who are known
for their charitable endeavors,
who would think nothing of,
for instance, writing a $28 million check,
to help victims
of methamphetamine abuse?
I have to think that your money
would be very welcome.
It wouldn't make any sense
coming from us.
It certainly would.
My children are blameless victims
of their monstrous father.
A man who you once knew
quite well.
Call it a beau geste,
call it liberal guilt,
call it whatever you want, but do it.
And you are not to spend
a single dime of your own money.
If there are taxes or lawyers' fees owed,
you will take it right from here.
They use my money, never yours.
Okay, Walt, sure.
That sounds reasonable.
So, what happens next?
I guess we shake on it,
and I leave.
I can trust you to do this.
Yes.
Absolutely, you can.
Don't move. Don't--
Don't dare move a muscle.
You don't want them to think that
you're trying to get away. Just breathe.
Just this afternoon,
I had an extra $200,000
that I would have loved dearly
to leave on top of this table.
Instead, I gave it to the two best
hit men west of the Mississippi.
Now,
whatever happens to me tomorrow,
they'll still be out there.
Keeping tabs.
And if,
for any reason,
that my children
do not get this money,
a kind of countdown
will begin.
Maybe a day or so later,
maybe a week, a year,
when you're going for a walk in Santa
Fe or Manhattan or Prague, wherever,
and you're talking
about your stock prices
without a worry in the world.
And then suddenly,
you'll hear the scrape
of a footstep behind you,
but before you can
even turn around:
Pop!
Darkness.
Cheer up, beautiful people.
This is where you get to make it right.
Oh, yeah, right.
You know, I don't exactly know
how to feel about all this.
For real, yo.
Whole thing felt kind of shady,
you know, like, morality-wise?
Totally.
How do you feel now?
Better.
Yeah, definitely improving.
What's this I hear
about blue meth
still being out there?
What do you mean?
Have you heard anything?
Is it still being sold?
Yeah.
By whom?
It's you, right?
I mean, aren't you
still cooking?
Damn, man.
We were sure it was you,
because that shit is choice, yo.
Better than ever.
I mean, um, you know.
Jesse.
Seriously?
You said he moved to Alaska.
That's what I heard.
Right on, Jesse.
Passing the torch.
Damn, man, couldn't he at least
throw a brother a bone?
Whoa, what happened there?
It's my birthday.
Yeah? Well, happy birthday.
It's easy money. Till we catch you. Say
the word, I'll take you on a ride-along.
You can watch us
knock down a meth lab.
Get a little excitement
in your life. Heh, heh.
Yeah, someday.
Welcome. Would you like a menu?
No, thank you.
Chamomile tea with soy milk, please.
All right, you got it.
Hey, how you doing?
Good.
How's things?
Hey, I like your...
Shirt.
My blouse?
Nice. Yeah, I like the color.
That's a nice color on you.
It's kind of a--
I don't know exactly what you'd call it.
It's kind of a cornflower blue.
Before you say or do anything,
just hear me out.
Todd.
Nobody knows that I'm here.
Just listen for two minutes,
and then I'll leave. Please.
No. Please.
Just two minutes of your time.
That's all I ask.
Please.
You're running out of
methylamine, aren't you?
I can do the math.
You've been at it long enough.
You must be running low.
I have a new method
that requires no methylamine.
It's easy, and it will keep you in business.
And, Todd, I could teach it to you.
How did you know
to find us here?
Ten a.m.
Every Tuesday morning,
you and I met here.
You're rather
schedule-oriented, I guess.
Sorry.
I need the money.
I've spent almost all of mine already,
just trying to stay
one step ahead of the police.
Mr. White, I don't think there's--
How much would it cost us?
Nothing short of a million.
And believe me, for this,
that is giving it away.
I think Jack should hear this.
Yeah, I don't know.
Now, listen, I can come up
there tonight and talk to him.
He'd get it.
This is a win-win situation.
Hi, what can I get for you two?
He's just leaving.
Good seeing you again.
Take care.
For you?
I'm good.
And I need more stevia.
Okay, no disrespect to the man,
but doing business with him?
Right now, that's not--
Of course we're not
doing business with him.
Todd, please.
Don't make me walk you through this.
Jesus. Did you look at him?
You'd be doing him a favor.
Hello, please record after the tone.
Truce, all right?
Skyler, I have news about Walt,
and you need to hear it,
so if you're there, pick up.
Skyler--
Hey.
What's up?
Walt's in town.
Yeah?
That car they thought he stole
in New Hampshire,
they found it in a Denny's
parking lot right on Central.
And your next-door neighbor,
on the right-- What's her name, Becky?
Becky's on the left. Carol's on the right.
Becky, Carol, whatever.
She saw him at your old house.
Just this morning, plain as day.
He's there, walking out of your house,
and he calls her by name.
He didn't hurt her, did he? He didn't--?
No, he's just like, "Hey, Becky!"
Or Carol, whatever.
She said he looked exactly
like the Unabomber.
But she's positive it was him.
They're getting calls from all over town.
He's here, he's there,
he's going to blow up city hall.
He has some sort of manifesto.
He wants to be on the news.
Who's making these calls? Him?
There are two or three voices.
They're not sure if they're crank calls
or people he's put up to it,
or if they're actual anonymous tips.
It's stretching them thin,
which is maybe the point.
As far as I'm concerned,
there are three places that he would go:
To you, to me, or Flynn.
Right.
They're watching the high school.
They're probably watching
your place too.
I mean,
I know that's what Hank would do.
There is no way Walt's getting to you.
They are absolutely going to catch him.
No doubt about it.
That arrogant asshole thinks he's some
criminal mastermind, but he's not.
But on the off chance...
Yeah.
On the million-to-one chance,
you be on the lookout, okay?
Thanks.
You got it.
Five minutes.
You didn't kill anybody
sneaking in here, did you?
You didn't hurt anybody?
No.
Didn't have to.
You look terrible.
Yeah.
But I feel good.
So talk.
Why are you here?
It's over.
And I needed
a proper goodbye.
Not our last phone call.
So you're going to the police?
They'll be coming to me.
If you're in custody,
what stops those people
from coming back?
When--
When I still had the house,
three men came
in the middle of the night,
wearing masks, threatening
Holly and Flynn and me.
They told me not to talk about
that woman at the car wash,
and if you're in custody--
They're not coming back.
Not after tonight.
What's tonight?
We don't want your money, Walt.
I thought Flynn made that clear.
He did.
And I don't have any to give you.
I spent the last of it getting here.
All I have to give you
is this.
Call the DEA once I leave.
Tell them I was here.
That I forced my way in.
Tell them...
Tell them I wanted
bacon and eggs on my birthday,
and that I gave you that ticket.
Those numbers
are GPS coordinates.
For what?
A burial site.
That's where they'll
find Hank and Steve Gomez.
It's where I buried our money.
And the men who stole it from us,
the men who still have it,
they murdered Hank and Steve
and put them in that hole.
Now, you trade that
for a deal with the prosecutor.
You get yourself out of this.
Skyler.
All the things that I did,
you need to understand--
If I have to hear
one more time
that you did this for the family--
I did it for me.
I liked it.
I was good at it.
And
I was
really...
I was alive.
Flynn will be home soon.
Before I go,
may I see her?
Whoo.
Damn, man, this thing's a classic.
What block you got in it?
The 500 or the 425?
Couldn't tell you.
Well...
Five hundred.
That's the one you want.
No replacement for displacement.
Where to?
To the clubhouse.
Go ahead, just park it
right in front over here.
No, no, no, just straight in, man.
Just-- What are--?
All right, fine, here, whatever.
Hey, how you doing?
Turn around,
put your arms out like this.
While you're at it,
why don't you lift your shirt up,
give us a spin?
Christ, I'm not wearing a wire.
Okay?
My wallet and keys?
Yeah, you'll get them back. Just relax.
Stay here.
Keep your eyes open.
Jesus, look at you with
that head of hair. Is that real?
Yes.
That's not a wig? Seriously?
No.
What were you doing before,
shaving it?
Yes.
Christ, that is one fine
head of hair.
I mean, otherwise,
you look like shit, but--
Hello to you too, Jack.
Now, can we talk business?
I don't think so, no.
Did Todd tell you what I'm offering?
Yeah, he told me.
The thing is
we're not really in the market.
You're low on methylamine.
What happens then?
No, we'll get more.
That Quayle woman's got her own setup.
The heat's off her.
She can break loose a barrel.
It ain't broke, so why fix it?
Todd, please, would you
explain things to your uncle?
Explain to him the benefit
of what I'm offering.
You really shouldn't
have come back, Mr. White.
I'm sorry.
Wait. Jack.
Where do you want it?
I don't know,
anywhere but my living room?
Take him out back.
Jack, look, you owe me.
You owe me.
Hey, hey, hey.
Let's go.
I owe you, what for?
Jesse Pinkman. You promised
you would kill him, and you didn't.
Instead, you partnered with him.
All right.
You're his partner now--
Whoa, stop.
Partners? What are you
talking about?
He's alive, isn't he?
He's cooking for you.
What, are you gonna lie?
Him being alive
is not him and me being partners.
Not by a damn sight.
What, you think
I'd partner with a rat?
Where is that little piece of shit?
He's finishing up a batch.
Go get him. Bring him here.
Uncle Jack--
No. No, no, no.
This one here, calling me a liar?
He just insulted you,
he insulted me, all of us.
Jesus. Hustle it up. Come on.
Let's get this over with.
I'm gonna show you
just how wrong you are.
Then I'm putting that bullet
in your head myself.
Yeah, you see what I'm
talking about, you son of a bitch?
Now, does this look
like a partner to you?
Come here. Take a look.
Come here!
Take a look at him.
Have a gander.
This is my partner.
Right, partner? Right, buddy?
Hardworking, good partner.
Fifty-fifty partner.
Can you hurry this shit up?
Make it quick?
Toddy, get him off, would you?
Yeah, Toddy, get them both off.
Uncle Jack.
Jesus.
Mr. White.
Wait. Wait.
You want your money, right?
You wanna know where it is?
You pull that trigger, you'll never--
Do it.
You want this.
Say the words.
Say you want this!
Nothing happens until I hear you say it.
I want this.
Then do it yourself.
Pick up the phone.
Hello?
Is it done?
Is he gone?
Yeah, it's done.
He's gone.
They're all gone.
Todd? Who is this?
It's Walt.
How are you feeling?
Kind of under the weather?
Like you've got the flu?
That would be
the ricin I gave you.
I slipped it into that stevia crap
that you're always putting in your tea.
Oh, my God.
Well,
goodbye, Lydia.