Everything's set. They're waiting for us
at the Great Northern.
Yeah, a large house made of wood,
surrounded by trees.
The house is filled with many rooms
each alike,
but occupied by different souls
night after night.
- The guests will be in the lobby?
- Full cooperation.
Hawk, you got that warrant
for Harold Smith's apartment?
On my way
as soon as I finish my coffee.
Hawk,
Gordon has mentioned pages...
What I mentioned were pages
found near the bloody towel
down the train tracks
from the crime site
were from a diary.
Donna Hayward
spoke of Harold Smith
having a secret diary
of Laura Palmer's.
Could be important.
Let me know what you dig up.
Gordon, I understand you're...?
Gordon, I understand
you're on your way to Bend, Oregon?
I'm over to Bend, Oregon,
official business, real hush-hush.
Good luck to all of you.
- Coop.
- Gordon.
Take good care of Mike.
It was real nice meeting you fellas.
- Sheriff.
- Safe journey, chief.
Thanks.
No.
Sheriff? Sheriff!
Sheriff, what's the meaning of this?
What the hell is going on here?
Will somebody please tell me
what the hell is happening here?
What in the hell is going on?
Mr. Smith.
Harold Smith?
Morning.
- Good morning, dear.
- Good morning, Maddy.
Uncle Leland.
Aunt Sarah.
Sit. Oh, good, you got some coffee.
Good.
- Did you sleep well?
- Very well. Thanks.
I've been thinking.
I've really enjoyed my stay
and everything.
Aw.
But I really feel like it's time
for me to go home now.
To Missoula.
I've got my job and my apartment.
And I just...
...miss having a life of my own.
Uh-huh.
So I think I'll probably be driving
back home tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Well, we are going to miss you
very much.
- But we also understand completely.
- You do?
- We do.
- We do. Yes, we do.
You have been
such a wonderful help.
Yes, but now she has to think
about herself, honey.
She's got her own life.
Besides, you'll come back and visit,
won't you?
Oh, of course.
- I'll come galloping back often.
- Heh, heh, heh.
It's not like Missoula
was at the far end of the universe.
- No.
- Hardly.
Well, good then.
It's all right.
Just know that we love you
very much.
I love you too.
- Hey, what's that, a note?
- Yeah.
"I'm a lonely soul."
Poor guy.
It's a good thing
Andy didn't see this one.
Oh, yeah.
Take a look at this.
"This is the diary of Laura Palmer."
Pay dirt.
Well, we have bills here
that total $1,014.
Including the insurance money
that leaves you with...
Forty-two dollars.
- Forty-two dollars.
- That's a good start.
Forty-two dollars for the month?
How am I gonna make it?
How are we supposed to survive
on $42 a month?
We? Shelly, I can't keep telling
my mom and dad
that I'm spending the night
at Mike's.
What time is it?
I'm missing Economics as it is.
"We" meant me and Leo.
Bobby, you said
you were gonna take care of us.
I am, Shelly. I am.
I want you
to take the necklace back.
We don't have to do that.
I want you to take the necklace back.
We need the money.
Shelly, you're gonna
keep this necklace.
When am I ever gonna feel
glamorous enough to wear it?
Giving Leo a bath?
Feeding him his oatmeal?
What about his truck?
He's not gonna be cannonballing
down the highway anytime soon.
- The police impounded it.
- We can get it back.
They said if it was used
in the commission of a crime
it becomes property of the state.
- He wasn't charged with anything.
- I didn't make the rules.
Okay, okay.
It's like you're blaming me
for something.
I'm not blaming you. Come on.
Take it easy.
Leo was into a lot of different stuff
with a lot of different people.
He was in it for the money.
Bobby, look around you.
You really think that Leo had money?
Yes, I do.
Having a look at this checkbook,
I don't think he ever stepped foot
into a bank.
He must have been hiding it
somewhere.
He's alive.
New shoes.
Bobby, he's alive.
- He ain't alive, Shelly.
- But he talked.
It's only... That was a burp.
He probably has gas.
You call that a burp?
New shoes.
Did he buy any shoes lately
by any chance?
No.
He had me take in a pair of boots
for repair.
- When?
- Last week.
- Have you got a receipt?
- Yeah, why?
I don't know.
Shelly, go get that receipt.
New shoes.
Want some new shoes, Leo?
Give us what we want,
I'll buy you the whole damn shoe store.
New shoes.
Daddy, I know about
One-Eyed Jack's.
I'm sure I don't know
what you're talking about.
I know about Blackie,
I know about Emory Battis,
I know about Ronette,
and I know about Laura.
Okay.
I was there. I saw you.
Uh-huh.
You remember Prudence?
I wore a little white mask.
I need to ask you some questions.
Ask away.
How long have you owned
One-Eyed Jack's?
Five years.
Did you know Laura worked there?
She was only there for a brief time.
- Did you know?
- Yes.
Did you in any way encourage her
to work there?
No. I had no idea.
She asked if she could work
in the department store.
Battis sent her without my knowing.
Did you sleep with her?
Did you?
Yes.
Did you kill her?
I loved her.
Norma, can I talk to you
for a second?
Sure. What's up?
Um...
With Leo coming home and all...
...I'm supposed to be there
to watch him.
And it looks like
it's gonna be a full-time thing.
So I was thinking
that I have to quit my job.
Just for a little while anyway.
I'm sorry.
I promised myself
I wasn't gonna do this.
It's all right, sweetheart.
I just feel so bad.
I love you. I love working here.
I don't wanna let you down.
You're not gonna let me down.
I'm not?
Look, Shelly, you've got your own life
to worry about.
I'll be fine here.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Now, you look after yourself.
When you're ready,
you can come right back.
It'll be like you haven't even
missed a day.
You'll let me come back?
You just try to take a job someplace
else and see what happens.
I don't know what to say.
Don't say anything.
And I told him I'd been traveling
with my parents,
but now I wanted to register
for spring semester.
Oh, Eddie, let's sit at the counter.
I'm just dying for a chocolate shake,
aren't you?
Hi, Norma.
Say, how long have you
been working here?
Well, it's 20 years this April.
Oh, you kidder.
What a kidder. Heh, heh, heh.
Well, it's been about, uh, six weeks,
isn't that right, Norma?
- Huh?
- About six weeks.
- Oh, yeah, that's right.
- Well, you see?
When your parents drag you off
to Europe or someplace for a month,
then when you get back,
it's like you've been away forever.
Two chocolate shakes,
please, Norma.
- Coffee for me.
- Extra whipped cream on mine.
Hi.
- What's your name?
- Shelly.
Are you in our class at school?
I don't think so.
Oh.
I'll get the shake and coffee.
- Europe?
- Yeah.
My parents loved it so much
they're still there.
Can you believe it?
And they said it was okay
for me to stay over at Eddie's.
Is it your parents' house
or mine, Eddie?
That's right.
Oh, say, Norma,
you're not mad or anything
because Eddie's sort of taking me out,
are you?
You and Ed? No. No.
Why should I be?
Oh, no reason.
Eddie told me you broke up.
It's just that...
...I'm just so sweet on him.
- Isn't he just the dreamiest?
- Nadine.
I can't wait
for the start of football season.
- Can you?
- No. Can't wait.
Me neither.
I am just so happy.
- Oh, Nadine.
- Oh, God, I'm sorry.
- How'd you do that?
- There goes another one.
There must've been a crack
in this glass from before.
- Golly.
- Don't count on it.
I'm so clumsy lately.
I can hardly believe it.
Shelly, get those Band-Aids,
and I'll get a towel.
Oh, Eddie.
I am so happy
I could just kiss you to death.
Oh, boy, Nadine.
I think she's at the diner. Shelly.
Shelly.
There he is, Mike.
The late Leo Johnson.
- Hank did this?
- He sure as hell did.
He shot him through that window
right there.
Leo, I went to the shoe shop.
I showed them the ticket,
and look what they gave me.
- New shoes.
- No, you knucklehead, old shoes.
Leo, he gets pretty fixated.
I hope he gets permanently fixated.
I know you too damn well, Leo.
Something about these shoes,
isn't there? Huh?
There's something
with these shoes.
I heard about people, you know,
muling stuff in their boot.
What, do you think
I didn't check these out?
Would you get a hammer?
Don't go anywhere, Leo.
Oh, my God.
- What is that, a tape?
- Don't.
Quit spitting, man.
Well, it's not money.
But who knows?
Diane, it's 2:47 p.m.
I'm in the conference room
at the sheriff's station
with the remains
of Laura Palmer's secret diary.
A great deal of it
has been mutilated.
Much of what I've been able
to decipher
supports the contention
of the one-armed man.
There are repeated references
to a Bob.
He was a threatening presence
in her life from early adolescence.
There are intimations of abuse
and molestation on a regular basis.
He is referred to,
on more than one occasion,
as a friend of her father's.
And I just uncovered this entry
dated less than two weeks
before her death:
"Someday I'm gonna tell the world
about Ben Horne.
I'm gonna tell them
who Ben Horne really is."
Yes?
- Audrey.
- I had to see you.
- I'm sorry if I'm interrupting you.
- How are you feeling?
- I spoke with my father.
- Yeah?
He was sleeping with her.
With Laura.
I don't know for how long,
maybe quite a while.
Holy smokes.
She was up at One-Eyed Jack's,
working there.
And he owns the place,
that's what I found out.
- He told you this?
- Yes.
What are you gonna do?
Harry.
Are you gonna arrest him?
Audrey, I don't want you
to say a word about this to anyone.
- Okay.
- Okay. Now, go on home.
What's going on?
Without chemicals he points.
This morning at the Great Northern,
Mike reached for his arm and fainted
just when a certain person
walked into the room.
Harry, we need a warrant.
A warrant for the arrest
of Benjamin Horne.
Good news, Mr. Tojamura.
My brother, Jerry,
spoke to your people in Osaka,
checked your references
at the Tokyo bank,
and the answer to your proposal,
my good friend,
is a big thumbs up.
We appreciate your promptness.
Speaking for the entire community
of Twin Peaks,
I cannot tell you how pleased we are
to welcome you
into the Ghostwood fold.
Thank you so much.
- Contract. For your perusal.
- And a fast approval I...
Sheriff.
- What is this?
- This is police business.
We'd like you to come with us.
Fine. I happen to be in a meeting.
Could you be a little more specific?
You're wanted for questioning
in the murder of Laura Palmer.
Is that specific enough for you?
You're insane. Insane.
Mr. Tojamura, I'm sure that this
is some dreadful mistake.
You can come quietly
or we can drag you through your lobby
in handcuffs.
Cooper, is this some sort
of sick joke?
Because if it is,
I know people in high places.
You'd better do what he says.
Go away.
Get out of here. Go on, go on.
I'm gonna go out for a sandwich.
No! No! No!
No! No!
You...
No! You can't do this to me.
- It's already done.
- You...
Leland.
Take him down to the holding cell.
We don't know what will happen
or when,
but there are owls
in the Roadhouse.
The Roadhouse.
Something is happening,
isn't it, Margaret?
Yes.
Oh!
Say, look here, buster,
you just watch it.
Since the moment we met,
I have been strangely attracted to you.
You just better get the hell out of here,
mister.
There's
something about your eyes, so warm...
...and deep.
And blue as the sky.
Dummy, it's me. It's me.
Catherine?
You look terrible.
Just terrible. Ha, ha, ha.
Tell your heart that I'm the one
Tell your heart it's me
- You heard about Harold Smith?
- Yeah.
It's not anybody's fault.
He was a sick man.
I think he was hurt inside
in a way I couldn't figure out.
Everybody's hurt inside.
His whole life was in that house,
and I violated that.
You were just trying to find out
about Laura.
James, he's dead.
He didn't deserve that.
Shadow in my house
The man, he has brown eyes
Sheriff Truman.
Love moves me
I want you
Rockin' back inside my heart
Maddy's leaving.
She is?
Yeah, she's gonna go home.
That's weird.
She never said anything to me.
Tell your heart you make me cry
Tell your heart don't let me die
I want you
Rockin' back inside my heart
Shadow in my house
Dust is dancing in the space
A dog and bird are far away
The sun comes up and down
Each day
It is happening again.
Hm.
Aunt Sarah?
Uncle Leland?
Aunt Sarah, Uncle Leland,
what is that smell?
It smells like something's burning.
Oh, my gosh. Aunt Sarah?
Shh! Shh!
Somebody, help me!
Help me!
Laura. Laura.
Laura. Laura. Laura.
Laura, my baby.
Laura. Laura.
Laura.
Leland says...
...you're going back to Missoula,
Montana!
Dust is dancing in the space
I'm so sorry.
The sun comes up and down
Each day
The river flows out to the sea
Love, don't go away
Come back this way
Come back and stay
Forever and ever