Diane, it is 4:28 a.m.
I have just been woken up
by the most God-awful racket,
which you can probably hear
over the sound of my voice.
Can you hear that?
Up until this moment, I've experienced
nothing at the Great Northern Hotel
but the most pleasant,
courteous service imaginable.
However, it just goes to prove the point
that once a traveler leaves his home,
he loses almost 100 percent
of his ability to control his environment.
Diane, I was wondering if you could
overnight express to me
two pair of those
Ear-Pillow silicone earplugs
which I used on my last trip
to New York.
Naturally, I didn't bring them with me
on this trip,
because I didn't feel
it would be necessary.
However...
Coffee?
Please.
- What's with the choir practice?
- Heh.
Business junket. From Iceland.
Got in about 3 this morning.
Ohh.
- They're on my floor.
- Lucky you.
It'll take them a day or two
to reset their biological clocks.
- Heh. Hope the herring holds out.
- Mm.
How are you?
Well, Audrey, to be perfectly honest,
I'm tired and a little on edge.
Oh.
I got a job.
Good for you.
And I thought maybe now
I could help you with your case.
Guess where I'm going...
Audrey, you'll have to excuse me
this morning.
I'm running late.
I only have time for coffee.
Well, maybe I could go with you.
Wednesdays were traditionally
a school day when I was your age.
I can't believe
you were ever my age.
I've got the pictures to prove it.
- How old are you?
- Eighteen.
We'll see you later, Audrey.
See you later.
Bye.
Ha, ha.
I'll see you later, Sons of Olden!
How do you say that?
My brother will love you guys.
Brother Ben, I bring you greetings
from the fertile treeless tundra
of Iceland.
We have had complaints
from nearly every guest in the hotel.
What are they on, nitrous oxide?
They are insane
for the Ghostwood Estates project.
I have had more serious fun
in two days with these Nordic animals.
And, Ben, I'm in love.
Her name is Heba.
She's a giant snow queen
with a smile
like a sunrise on an ice floe.
You could go blind looking at this girl.
Look at this.
You see what she gave me?
An entire leg of lamb.
- Jerry, come on.
- Is that beautiful?
Come on, look, you crush some garlic,
some fresh mint,
that's rotisserie heaven.
Come on, you gotta meet her.
Jerry, just grab some downtime,
will you?
We've laid in a gala reception
for your fair-haired boys tonight.
All of Twin Peaks'
best and brightest.
We're holding it in a phone booth?
And if we still need a kicker
to nail the sale, I'm thinking
that maybe they might enjoy
a little road trip up to, uh,
you-know-where. Ah?
Jack's. I am honored to know you.
Ben?
Leland, what are you doing here?
Well, I know there's a new
investment group arriving today.
If there's anything I can do...
Leland, the best thing that
you can do is follow doctor's orders.
Go home. You need your rest.
I just feel...
I just feel I need something
to occupy my mind.
Leland, will you take some time off,
for God's sakes?
Fly somewhere. Uh, take Sarah.
I'm afraid to go. I'm afraid.
Hawk, we're here
at Jacques Renault's apartment.
Get over here as soon as you can.
- Morning.
What do you got, Harry?
Jacques Renault's
a Canadian national.
He worked the lumber fields
this side of the border
until he put on a little excess tonnage
a couple of seasons ago.
That's when he started bartending
at the Roadhouse.
Harry,
are there any more doughnuts?
Sure. Andy.
Thank you.
Better wash that down
with a cup a joe.
I didn't get too much sleep last night.
Yeah, you do look a little peaked.
There's a large group of insane men
staying on my floor.
Jacques Renault turn up?
No one's seen him for two days.
We've canvassed the building
and the Roadhouse.
- I sent Hawk to roust his brother.
- I'll get back to you.
But it looks like Bernie's jumped bail.
There's no sign.
- Morning, Agent Cooper.
- Morning, doc.
The blood on the shirt you found here
is AB negative.
It's not Laura's blood.
So it was Jacques Renault's blood
on Leo Johnson's shirt. Hmm.
Hmm.
Oh. Thank you, Andy.
Mm.
What about Leo Johnson?
Could you hold this?
The APB went out last night.
Nothing yet.
- I need you to find out something.
- Could you give me a leg up here?
Sure.
What's Jacques Renault's blood type?
- Alley-oop.
- Unh.
Jacques Renault's blood
is AB negative.
Thanks, doc.
My pleasure.
Holy smoke. Flesh World again.
Yeah.
Harry, remember that ad
with the picture of Ronette Pulaski?
We traced that ad.
It came into the magazine
in a plain envelope, no name.
Well, the magazine's
a clearing-house.
Readers write letters
in response to the ads
and mail them in to the magazine.
The magazine forwards them on
to the advertisers.
No direct contact.
Ronette received her letters
at this post office box.
That's a local ZIP code.
Now, my guess is
that this post office box
will be registered
under the name of Jacques Renault.
Let's see
who was writing to Ronette.
Postmarked Georgia.
Good night.
I don't know.
The beard sort of ruins
the effect of the lingerie.
What do you think?
The guy's no Georgia peach.
Poor bastard.
By the way, Harry, did you notice
the picture of Leo Johnson's truck
on that page?
I love it when you cook for me.
Leo hates my cooking.
Leo missed the boat with you, baby.
The biggest mistake of your life
was dropping out of the 11th grade
and marrying that road hog.
What would you do
if he walked in right now?
Come here.
Hey, Leo. How's it going, man?
What a surprise.
Now, Leo, Shelly tells me
that you don't like her cooking.
Tell you what, she and I,
we're gonna sit here
while you cook breakfast for us,
you hump.
And if you so much as utter
one harsh syllable
to this beautiful girl,
I'm gonna shoot your ugly face off,
okay, man?
Sheriff's deputy.
Now, Shelly,
you do exactly what we said,
and everything's gonna be fine.
Okay? Come here. Mm.
Oh, hi, Andy. Come on in.
Hi, Shelly.
Do you know
when Leo might be back?
Is he in some kind of trouble?
No, we just wanna talk to him.
This wouldn't be about Laura, would it?
Why do you say that?
Well, I heard him talking
to this guy, Jacques, the night he left.
Jacques Renault?
Yeah. They were outside arguing.
I couldn't hear exactly, but they did
seem to be arguing about her,
and then they drove off together.
Shelly, you call us
the minute he gets in touch with you.
Okay, I will. Thanks for stopping by.
- How'd I do?
- You did great. Oh.
You drive me crazy.
- Hello?
- Hi.
Hi, Leo. Where you calling from?
Has anybody come by?
What's that?
Is anybody looking for you?
Why would anybody
be looking for you?
Are you sure?
You know how paranoid you get
when you've been popping bennies
on the road a couple of days.
So when are you coming home?
Soon. Everything okay?
Yeah, everything's fine, Leo.
Come on home.
I miss you, Shelly.
I miss you too.
Hey, good-looking.
Hope you don't mind my coming.
Oh, no.
Nadine won't be back
from that patent attorney
over there in Fairvale
for a couple of hours.
Ah. The famous
silent drape runners.
She's already spending the millions.
Well, I have to put gas in my car
like everyone else, right?
You bet.
I didn't wanna tell you on the phone,
but Hank got his parole.
Okay.
He'll be coming home. I mean, back.
I only saw him
a minute before the hearing.
He seemed so hopeful.
I didn't wanna say anything.
You don't have to explain.
Have you said anything
to Nadine yet?
Haven't yet.
Waiting for me to go first?
No.
It's just that, uh, Nadine's not well.
What are you saying?
I don't know.
I think I do.
I don't ever wanna hurt you, babe.
Maybe that's our trouble, Ed.
We never wanna hurt anyone.
We never just take what we want.
There's a part of me
that's beginning to think
that this is how it is
when you get to the end of your life
and that you don't have anything
to show for it.
Norma.
Don't call me.
I mean, not for a while, okay?
Okay.
I love you, Ed.
I can remember
when you were just a little girl.
So did my father speak to you?
Yes, yes, he did.
And I can't tell you how excited we are
to have you come on board
and put in a hitch with us
down here at our flagship.
So, what did you have in mind
for me?
Well, Audrey,
as per your father's suggestion,
starting low, aiming high, et cetera,
we thought perhaps
the Wrapping Department,
gifts, et cetera.
Part-time, after school.
No, no, no.
Emory, may I speak frankly?
Oh, please do.
Let's talk retail.
Sales?
Perfume.
One of our more, uh,
sensitive areas.
Expensive items,
delicate customer relations.
I'm afraid I've got my heart
set on it, Emory.
Heh. I'd have to talk to your father.
Emory, here's what we're gonna do.
You're gonna tell my father
that I'm busy as a bee
wrapping boxes with the drones.
Then you're gonna put me to work
this afternoon
behind the perfume counter,
because if you don't,
I'm gonna rip my dress in half
and scream at the top of my lungs
and tell my father
that you made a pass at me.
Does that help
to clear things up for you?
Yes.
Yes, what?
Yes, Miss Horne.
Shall we get started
on the paperwork?
James. I got your note.
Are you all right?
Donna,
there's some things I gotta say.
I told you
that my dad died when I was 10.
He didn't die.
He was a musician.
We were living on the West Coast.
He was a bum,
and he ran off on me and my mom.
I'm sorry.
My mom was a writer.
She was really good.
Poems and short stories.
She's an alcoholic.
If you have a problem with this,
I know you didn't ask to hear it.
I don't have a problem. You tell me.
It's true she was out of town this week,
but she wasn't traveling.
What she does
is she goes to another town,
shacks up in some cheap hotel
with a couple of bottles
and picks up guys and...
It's all right.
I'm telling you this because I don't
wanna have any secrets from you.
I don't want there to be any lies
between us.
It's the secrets people keep
that destroy any chance they have
of happiness,
and I don't want us to be like that.
We won't. We won't be.
We have to do what's right.
What you said yesterday was true.
If we don't do everything we can
to figure out what happened to Laura,
it'll never go away our whole lives.
We will, James.
She's out there,
wandering like a restless spirit.
I feel it too.
We owe it to her.
At least they're fresh.
Here you go, Gary.
Oh, thanks.
- Here you go, Scott.
- Thank you.
There you are.
What do you wanna mark this?
Mark it duplicate.
Do we have one like it?
Yeah, the same stain.
We had it before.
Mark it duplicate.
Hmm. Red drapes.
That PO Box was registered
to Jacques Renault.
Those are the letters responding
to Ronette's ad in the magazine.
Let's see if there's something
from someone we know.
Hawk, hand me that magazine,
would you?
What is it?
Two different ad numbers mailed
to the same post office address.
Ronette's and one other.
Yeah, here it is.
"Young student requires education
in the ways of love.
Only generous mature men
need apply."
It's Laura.
You see some identifying mark?
- The drapes.
- Drapes?
Red drapes, Harry, from my dream.
Now, why would an apartment dweller
like Jacques
buy 50 gallons of heating oil?
Yeah, yeah, I already got it.
To heat a log cabin.
Harry, you're all right.
Jacques' brother said something
about a place up near the state line.
Fellas, let's pack a lunch.
We're taking a walk in the woods.
Madeleine.
- Hi.
Hi. I'm Madeleine Ferguson.
My friends call me Maddy.
This is really nice of you guys.
I don't really know anybody in town
except Aunt Sarah and Uncle Leland.
And the mood at the house,
you can probably guess,
isn't that great right now.
Would you like something to drink?
A cherry Coke would be great.
You got it.
Madeleine.
If I said that you can't really say
a word of this to anyone, not a soul,
not even your aunt or uncle,
would that be okay with you?
It sounds like some big secret.
It is.
James and I knew Laura
better than anyone did.
She was in some kind
of terrible trouble before she died,
worse than any of us could imagine.
What?
Well, I'd rather not say too much
about things we can't prove yet.
You said you can't prove it yet.
We loved Laura.
We're afraid that the truth
might never come out
or that the person who killed her
might never be caught.
We've sworn on her memory
not to let that happen.
My God. You know who did it?
We have some ideas.
We wanted to talk to you about this
because we need your help.
What do you want me to do?
Laura used to talk about
a secret hiding place she had
somewhere in her house,
maybe in her room.
I'm not really sure.
But nobody else knew about it.
We think she might have
left something there
that could lead us to the killer.
I'll help you.
You will?
The day before she died,
I had a feeling
that Laura was in trouble.
I've always felt close to her.
That's why I came here.
You know,
I didn't really know Laura that well,
but I feel like I do.
Our folks were always telling us
how much alike we were.
Will you call me
if there's anything I can do?
I don't think there'll be any problem.
This is really great.
Call me Maddy.
- Hi.
- Hi, Norma.
We look like a couple
of refugee beauty queens.
You don't know how really
good-looking you are.
I never felt so glamorous.
Hope I don't chip a nail
slinging plates around.
Hi, Norma.
Hello, Hank.
Surprised to see me, huh?
Yes.
Is that Leo's girlfriend?
Wife.
That Leo. So impulsive.
Not much meat on her, though.
Hey, I don't expect a kiss
or anything.
I figure I gotta earn my way
back into your heart.
But, Norma, I intend to try.
So where do I start?
Washing dishes will be fine.
Can I finish my coffee first, boss?
Oh, no. Oh, no. No.
You little Froot Loop.
You're done! Done!
Don't ever cross me.
Tune in tomorrow for Invitation to Love.
He's been spending more and more
of his time alone in his room.
It's become much more difficult
to engage him in conversation.
Terrible mood swings.
We've been told by the school that his
attendance has become erratic at best.
And then there's the matter
of public fighting,
both at the Roadhouse
and at the funeral.
Are you using drugs, Bobby?
Nope.
- Alcohol.
- Alcohol's a drug.
- Well, that's not what he meant.
- Alcohol doesn't count?
Everybody drinks.
Are you unhappy, Bobby?
Shouldn't I be?
Well, that's not for me to say.
Have you ever killed anybody?
- Have you?
- My father has.
- During wartime.
- That's different.
Different from what?
Perhaps I should spend
a few minutes with Bobby alone.
This is supposed to be
family counseling.
Well, and I'll need to spend some time
with each member of the family alone,
but Bobby first.
- Fair enough.
- Whatever you say.
Bobby, let's just cut the crap, huh?
Okay, so your parents
don't understand
what you're going through right now.
Heh. That's a good one.
Let's talk about Laura.
Okay. Let's talk about Laura.
Bobby, what happened the first time
that you and Laura made love?
What the hell kind of question
is that?
Bobby, did you cry?
Did I what?
And then what did Laura do?
Did she laugh at you?
Were you very sad
when Laura died?
- Laura wanted to die.
- How do you know that?
Because she told me.
What else did she tell you?
Did she tell you
there was no goodness in the world?
She said people tried to be good,
but they were really sick and rotten,
her most of all.
And every time she tried to make
the world a better place,
something terrible came up
inside her
and pulled her back down into hell.
It took her deeper and deeper
into the blackest nightmare.
And every time, it got harder
to go back up to the light.
Did you sometimes have the feeling
that Laura was harboring
some awful secret?
Yeah.
Bad enough that she wanted to die
because of it?
Yes.
Bad enough that it drove her
to consciously try to find
people's weaknesses
and prey on them,
tempt them, break them down,
make them do terrible,
degrading things?
- Yes.
- Laura wanted to corrupt people.
Because that's how she felt
about herself.
Yes.
Is that what happened to you,
Bobby?
Is that what Laura did to you?
She wanted so much.
She made me sell drugs
so she could have them.
This way. Through here.
Watch your step there, city boy.
Thanks, Harry.
What is it, Hawk?
Is that the cabin we're looking for?
Maybe, maybe not.
You might wanna
hang back a step, doc.
Huh. Might want to, anyway.
About time you got here.
They move so slowly
when they're not afraid.
Come on, then.
My log does not judge.
I've got tea.
I've got cookies. No cake.
Well, that's very kind of you, ma'am,
but I don't believe that...
What kind of cookies?
Sugar.
The owls won't see us in here.
A cup of tea would be very nice.
Shut your eyes
and you'll burst into flames.
Thanks, Margaret.
We'll let it steep.
Wait for the tea.
The fish aren't running.
You've been expecting us,
Margaret?
You're two days late.
But that's your concern.
My log saw something.
Something significant.
What did your log see?
Tea first. Then be ready.
Thank you.
- My husband was a logging man.
- Oh?
He met the devil.
Fire is the devil
hiding like a coward in the smoke.
It was the day after the wedding,
wasn't it, Margaret?
The wood holds many spirits,
doesn't it, Margaret?
You can ask it now.
What did you see that night?
The night Laura Palmer was killed?
Shh.
I'll do the talking.
Dark.
Laughing.
The owls were flying.
Many things were blocked.
Laughing. Two men.
Two girls.
Flashlights pass by in the woods
over the ridge.
The owls were near.
The dark was pressing in on her.
Quiet then.
Later, footsteps.
One man passed by.
Screams far away.
Terrible. Terrible.
One voice.
- Man or girl?
- Girl.
Further up. Over the ridge.
The owls were silent.
The two girls
were Laura and Ronette.
The two men, Jacques, maybe Leo.
Maybe.
Who's the third man?
Do you hear it?
This way.
And there's always music in the air.
Waldo.
There's film in here.
Blood.
One-Eyed Jack's.
Evening, Mr. and Mrs. Showel.
- Okay. Go right ahead.
- Thank you.
Good evening.
- Catherine Martell and spouse.
- Mm-hm.
Go easy on the sauce tonight,
okay, Cathy?
Couple of belts and even you
might start to look good to me.
Of course,
the modern age has changed forever
the way your people live,
Mr. Thorson.
But it would be my guess
that there still remains
a tremendous vestigial interest
in the legends and folklore
of ancient Iceland.
Vestigial. Absolutely.
Heba, did you know that was
an American figure of speech?
No, Jerry. Ha, ha.
Heba, Heba.
You never heard that before?
No, Jerry. Ha-ha-ha.
Do you realize the incredible potential
that could result
from our taking a mutual dip
in each other's respective gene pools?
Heba, I wanna cook for you.
Very, very good. That's funny.
So he says, "What do you get when
you cross a Norwegian with a Swede?
A socialist who wants to be king."
Well, I can remember it was,
I think, oh, somewhere in the '50s,
I came through your country.
Beautiful, beautiful.
Not many trees, though,
you know, but...
Hmm.
Would you excuse me?
Of course.
Meet me in my office.
Give me two minutes to break away.
- Hell hath no fury.
- What?
Two minutes.
Ah, Thor,
I've been meaning to ask you,
are you familiar
with the word luhamsta?
Catherine, we agreed,
no scenes in front of the guests.
Let's keep the melodrama
to a minimum.
The next thing I know, you're polishing
my shoes with Dom Pérignon.
Fill me in. What's eating you?
Why did you have this
thousand-dollar poker chip
from you-know-where
in your pants yesterday?
I thought you preferred women
with certain experience.
Hmm.
Jerry gave me that.
It's a good-luck charm.
I thought I'd lost it.
I'm so relieved that you found it.
Are you quite finished?
Yes.
In that case...
Oh. Let's burn the mill.
Let's do it tonight.
No, my love.
We'll give Josie
one last chance to sell.
Tomorrow.
Failing that,
I have retained the services
of a qualified professional.
Breath mint?
Now, let me get this straight.
Your entire country
is above the timberline?
Folks, ladies and gentlemen,
can I have your attention, please?
Can I have your attention?
Heh. First off, I wanna thank you all
for turning out
to welcome our neighbors
from the magical isle of Iceland.
We are all Icelanders.
The Ghostwood Estates project
is an important part of our future
here in Twin Peaks,
and there's no one we'd rather have
as partners in our future than...
What...?
Dance with him.
It is serious. Dance with him.
All right.
Jerry, what's going on?
Get Jacoby, get a net,
but get him out of my life.
What are they doing?
Jerry. Jerry.
Gather round.
Donna? It's Maddy.
I was looking in Laura's room
and I remembered
when we were younger, she used
to hide cigarettes in her bedpost.
The top of one of the posts
screws off.
I found a tape in her hiding place.
Leland? Where did you go?
I'll meet you and James tomorrow.
- Okay. And bring a tape recorder.
- Leland?
Did anyone see you come in here?
No.
You do realize the risk
if anyone sees us.
This was hidden in her desk
where you said it would be.
- Then we can proceed.
- When?
Tomorrow night.
Over here. Told you to mind the store,
Leo, not open your own franchise.
- Hank, I...
- Do as you're told, Leo.
Next time, you'll watch me take
your little chippy apart before I kill you.
Get me a beer, Shelly.
Honey, what happened?
Are you okay?
- Just get me a damn beer!
- Aah!
Get up and...
What the hell are you doing
with that?
You're not gonna hurt me again.
Don't touch me.
Don't come near me, Leo.
You stupid little slut.
You haven't got the guts.
Reach over and turn on the light.
Don't make me leave.
Please, don't make me leave.