Yeah.
Yeah, his hair was long.
Filthy, gray-on-gray, long hair.
I saw him, at the foot of Laura's bed.
He looked like an animal.
- Had you ever seen this man before?
- No, never.
His face. My God, his face.
Sarah, did you tell them
about the necklace?
- You're gonna love that one.
- What necklace?
She's had two visions.
Go ahead, Sarah.
Leland.
Sarah.
It's night.
A flashlight beam
moves across the ground.
Then a hand,
a gloved hand,
lifts a rock
and takes out a necklace.
Broken in half.
It was Laura's.
Invitation to Love.
Don't fight it, Chet.
You know as well as I
there's still something between us.
There always will be.
For God's sake, Emerald.
That may be true,
but I'm married to your sister now.
It's wrong.
Well, you always said
you could never tell us apart, so...
Morning, Lucy. What's going on?
Uh, thanks to Jade,
Jared decided not to kill himself.
And he's changed his will, leaving the
Towers to Jade instead of Emerald,
but Emerald found out about it,
and now she's trying to seduce Chet
to give her the new will
so that she can destroy it.
Montana's planning
to kill Jared at midnight,
so the Towers will belong
to Emerald and Montana,
but I think she's going to double-cross
him and he doesn't know it yet.
Poor Chet.
What's going on here?
Uh, Agent Cooper's in
the conference room with Dr. Jacoby.
Thank you.
Lucy, why couldn't I spend the night
last night?
Will you be having coffee,
Deputy Brennan?
Was Laura Palmer seeing you
because she was addicted to cocaine?
Agent Cooper, I'd like to help you,
but, uh, I got a little problem here.
Look, maybe there's some
sort of hula we can do
around my doctor-patient
confidentiality, huh?
It is safe to say she came to you
because she was having problems?
Oh, my, yes.
Were her problems
of a sexual nature?
Agent Cooper,
the problems of our entire society
are of a sexual nature.
Tibet. Hm.
You know, my abiding interests
lie to the east as well,
but only as far as, uh, Hawaii.
Ancient Hawaiians often turned to the
soothing rhizome of the ginger plant
to ease the pain
of profound confusion.
Which, more often than not,
was sexual.
Ginger is nonaddictive. Cocaine is.
Look, the fact that Laura Palmer
sought medication,
no matter how dubious,
was actually a positive sign.
Dr. Jacoby, I understand
you cared deeply for Laura Palmer.
Why is it that you won't help us?
My own personal investigation,
I suspect,
will be ongoing for the rest of my life.
Laura had secrets.
And around those secrets,
she built a fortress that...
Well, that in my six months
with her I was not able to penetrate,
and for which I consider myself
an abject failure.
Doctor, did Laura ever discuss
Bobby Briggs
or James Hurley with you?
Yeah, they were boys.
Laura was a woman.
She had sex with three men
the night she was murdered.
- Were you one of them?
- Heh.
No.
Who killed her, Dr. Jacoby?
The night after Laura died,
I followed a man that, uh,
Laura had spoken to me about.
He was driving a red Corvette.
I followed him to the Old Sawmill Road
and then I lost him.
And that, gentlemen,
is all I can tell you.
Agent Cooper,
there's a Gordon Cole on the phone.
He says you're expecting his call.
Should I put him through?
Yes, Lucy, put him through.
Thank you, doctor. That will be all.
You'll be in town, doctor?
Well, I'm planning a pilgrimage
to Pebble Beach,
but that's not till
the end of the month.
Hang loose, haoles.
Does Leo Johnson
drive a red Corvette?
Yes.
- How we doing on Jacques Renault?
- There's an APB on him.
His brother made bail this morning.
I got an all-points on him too.
Harry, this is my supervisor.
Good morning, Gordon.
How are we doing?
Cooper, where do we start?
The Palmer girl or Albert's
new best friend, Harry Truman?
- Laura Palmer.
- Albert has been very busy.
The twine he found on her upper arms
is a common household variety.
Finley's Fine Twine.
- And the twine on her wrists?
- Definitely not a match. No ID yet.
And those marks on her shoulders?
- Bird bites.
- Bird bites?
He'll also be faxing a reconstruction
of the plastic fragment
from her stomach.
Great, tell Albert
we're anxiously awaiting his results.
Now for the bad news, Coop.
I've got an O.O.J. and an A.F.O. here
from Albert
concerning his mano a mano
with the local Sheriff Truman.
Albert wants this guy's badge, Coop.
Gordon, here's how it is.
You know Albert.
In my opinion, Sheriff Truman
displayed the patience of a saint
not clocking him
a day earlier than he did.
He wants it filed
with the U.S. attorney.
- File it under F for "forget it."
- Cooper.
- Tell Albert if he wants to pursue this...
- Coop.
- I'll fight him
all the way to Washington.
- Don't get excited and hang up, now.
- I'll talk to you later, Gordon.
Thanks. Uh, I didn't get
a whole lot of sleep last night.
Harry, the last thing I want you
to worry about while I'm here
is some city slicker I brought into
your town relieving himself upstream.
- This is the man I saw in my dream.
- You saw this man?
I had an intuition that my dream and
Sarah Palmer's vision were connected.
I didn't go with you this morning
because I didn't wanna influence her.
I'm a strong sender.
The eyes were a bit closer together.
Deputy
Hawk calling in for Agent Cooper.
Hawk.
Right. Stay there.
Follow him if he moves.
Traveling east on Highway 12,
how long will it take us
to reach the Timber Falls Motel?
- Half an hour.
- Ten minutes.
- Depends how you go.
- Hawk's found our one-armed man.
I wish I could have seen
Josie's face.
Opening the safe
for her lawman Romeo
to show him the double set of books,
and all she finds
is the one I've been slowly cooking.
Where's the book
that spells bankruptcy?
Mm, I have more than one
hiding place.
Life goes on, trust me.
My desk upstairs.
There's a drop panel
in the top drawer.
Not even Pete the poodle
knows about that one.
I'm famished.
Let's get one thing straight.
I didn't spend 18 months
up the Amazon
dodging blow darts for my health.
I suppose room service is too much to
expect of this rusticated mildew farm.
You would prefer the Lumber Baron
Suite at the Great Northern?
I'd prefer getting on with setting
the torch to that damn mill.
Harry, he's here at the motel.
Room 101.
Last name's Gerard.
Now, when the mill goes up in smoke,
the headline that we're after is:
"Josie Packard torches
bankrupt mill in insurance fraud."
Not "Giant weenie roast
in the woods."
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
- Hm? Hm?
Mr. Gerard, it's the police. Open up.
What...? Jeez...
Gunplay? Sounds serious.
Mr. Gerard.
- Don't move.
- Oh, my God.
Keep your hands
where I can see them.
You, uh, let me know
if there's any bloodshed.
I'm going to give little Elvis a bath.
What do you mean, you don't
know him? You know this man.
Oh, no, sir. I've never seen
that man before in my life.
But you know something, he kind of
looks like somebody, doesn't he?
Mr. Gerard,
do you have a friend named Bob?
Bob Lydecker's just about
my best friend in the world.
Why have you been
at the hospital the past two days?
Bob's in a coma.
There was a Lydecker
assaulted three days ago outside a bar
in Lotown.
- That's Bob.
- Is your friend Bob a doctor?
He's just about the best
darn veterinarian in these parts.
Thanks.
He's clean. No record, no warrants.
Take a look at his car.
Your middle name is Michael.
Named after my uncle.
- How'd you lose the arm?
- Car accident.
I was on the road
from Memphis to, uh...
Someplace. Selling pharmaceuticals.
Pretty good job.
That's what I'm selling these days.
Everybody needs shoes.
- They're all for the right foot.
- That's my sample case.
Yeah. Two-day delivery, guaranteed.
We could certainly take care of
all your departmental needs.
The arm you lost,
did it have a tattoo?
What's this all about?
- I'm a shoe salesman.
- Settle down, Mr. Gerard.
He just asked you a question.
If you won't tell us, we can find out.
What did it say?
It said "Mom."
Harry.
What do you got?
Car was already staked out
when I got here.
It was Josie Packard.
I've been doing some research.
In real life, there is no algebra.
Maybe you should run away
and join the circus.
Escape.
I got a better idea.
A tall, dark and handsome stranger
falls madly in love with me,
takes me away to a life of mystery
and international intrigue.
You mean the FBI agent?
Dream on.
Maybe.
Or maybe he'll realize
that I'm the woman of his dreams
because I'm gonna help him
figure out who killed Laura.
- Is that so?
- Yeah.
And you're gonna help me.
Fact: Laura was seeing James Hurley
behind Bobby's back.
- What if she was?
- So it is true.
Fact: Laura had a sweet tooth
for nose candy.
Well, I guess
that's not such a big secret.
I didn't know Laura half as well as you,
and I knew the score.
Laura was wild.
Come on, will you help me?
What else have you figured out,
Sherlock?
The morning of the funeral,
Jacoby's talking to my brother Johnny,
trying to get him to go to the funeral.
So he tells Johnny that Laura's
in a better place now, blah, blah, blah.
And he knows that
because Laura was his patient.
Laura was seeing Jacoby?
It gets better.
You ever heard of One-Eyed Jack's?
Isn't that that Western
with Marlon Brando?
It's a place across the border.
They have girls working there.
Are you saying you think Laura
was one of them?
I don't know. But if it's true,
wouldn't you wanna know about it?
Well, it sure would explain
a few things.
You know, I think about it.
I think about Laura being in a place
like that and I get all shivery.
But it's like a hot cold,
like when you hold an ice cube
on your bare skin for a long time.
Audrey, I'll help you,
but whatever we find out, we have to
promise to keep it between ourselves.
- Our secret.
- It's a deal.
And I know exactly where to start.
Did you know Ronette and Laura
worked in the same place?
No.
The perfume counter
at my father's department store.
I've arranged for you to have a little
chat with Hank before the hearing.
He's glad you're here.
I hope I didn't come on
too strong yesterday.
I'll be sure to tell him how helpful
you've been, Mr. Mooney.
Haven't seen you for a while, Norma.
Been kind of busy.
- So, uh, business is good?
- Yeah.
You gotta back me up in there,
Norma, please.
I gotta get out.
It's starting to put the zap on me,
bigtime.
I know I have no right to ask
and you have no reason to believe me,
but I'll change.
I swear on my life, I have changed.
Give me a chance to prove it to you.
I've replayed it
in my mind a million times,
and I just don't have any answers.
A car in perfect condition
goes out of control.
A vagrant nobody knows is killed
while sleeping by the roadside.
Why?
Why did fate deal me this hand?
You are not incarcerated
for an act of fate, Mr. Jennings.
I accept that.
But it was fate, maybe in an odd way
even luck, that sent me to prison.
- Just as much as the car accident.
- What is your point?
I know I have a lot to make up for.
For the life I destroyed,
and for another life
I very nearly destroyed.
Mrs. Jennings, your husband
would be facing a difficult reentry.
How would you help him?
I own the Double R Diner
in Twin Peaks.
I can give him a job.
The boss is tough but fair.
And you would live together
as man and wife?
Well, he is my husband, isn't he?
Well, we have what we need here.
We'll make our decision
without the inmate present.
We'll let you know by 5:00 today.
Catch you later.
In my dream, Mike said he and Bob
lived above a convenience store.
Cooper, I'd think you'd be afraid
to go to sleep at night.
Hey, Hawk.
Andy, could you go into the One Stop
and get me some twine?
Okay.
No, that's not Dr. Lydecker.
- Does Dr. Lydecker treat birds?
- Why, yes, of course.
- Rhetta, we're ready for you.
- There are other vets in Twin Peaks.
Yes, but only one
has a best friend with one arm.
Harry, in the heat
of the investigative pursuit,
the shortest distance between two
points is not necessarily a straight line.
Andy, hand me that spool
of Finley's Fine Twine.
Ms. Loomer, we're gonna have to
confiscate your files.
What?
Harry, as clear as the signs
on the turnpike,
the bird that attacked Laura Palmer
is a client of this office.
I feel so bad for you.
I was watching you at the funeral
and my heart was aching.
I wanted to hold you so much.
That James Hurley.
He was seeing Laura
behind my back.
- I'm gonna fix him.
- Fix me first.
When is Leo due back?
Don't worry, bad boy.
I can hear his Vette a mile away.
Don't mess around with this, Shelly.
Where is he?
He's with his friend,
that creepy Jacques.
Jacques who?
That Canuck guy
that works at the Roadhouse.
- Leo and Jacques?
- What's the matter?
Gotta think. I gotta think...
Um, well, think later, Bobby.
I have to go back to the diner
in a half an hour.
I gotta tell you something.
What? What is it?
I've been onto this for a while.
I've been checking it out.
- It's pretty bad.
- Tell me.
Leo and Jacques are running drugs
across the border.
Cocaine. And they've been
selling them at school.
I knew it. I knew Leo
was messed up in something.
I think it's even possible
they were giving drugs to Laura.
Bobby,
I have to show you something.
This was in Leo's truck
two days after Laura was murdered.
You sure this is Leo's?
It has his initials sewn in the collar.
He makes me sew them
into everything.
Shelly, this...
This could be the answer
to our prayers.
What do you mean?
You don't need to know.
I'm gonna take this, okay?
You never saw this.
Say it. "I never saw it."
I never saw it.
Leo's not gonna be
a problem for us anymore.
Stay clear of him and keep quiet.
- I bought this.
- You know how to use it?
I thought you could teach me.
Teach me, Bobby.
Fellas, take them
right into the conference room.
Lucy, I need you
to go through these files
and pull out all the people
who own birds.
- How will I know they own birds?
- It'll say so on the cards.
Okay, I'll start going
through the files, then.
Agent Cooper, I'm so sorry.
I don't know what happened.
My gun just slipped out of my hand.
Andy, have you ever used
your weapon in the line of duty?
No, sir, I haven't.
I can't explain what happened.
I've been feeling a little high-strung.
Well, it was lack
of preparation. We'll take care of that.
Andy, get some ammunition
from the lockbox,
meet us downstairs
at the pistol range.
Lucy, did you hear what happened?
I feel so dumb.
I dropped my gun and it went off.
- Are you all right?
- Oh, yeah, I guess so, but...
I would like to chat, but I am now
under orders to examine these files,
so if you'll excuse me, please.
Laura Palmer's murder
was vicious and calculated.
There's no telling what we'll encounter
bringing a suspect to ground.
After Andy's mishap at the motel,
I wanna make absolutely certain
each of us is comfortable
and confident with our firearms.
Nice piece.
Actually, it's standard issue.
I made a few modifications.
How long has Lucy
been upset with Andy?
Body language?
In this case,
it was yelling through a megaphone.
- Six rounds apiece to start with, Andy.
- Okay.
Care to tell us
about you and Lucy, Andy?
Jeez, you can tell?
Not too many secrets
left around here.
She won't speak to me,
and I don't know why.
And I don't know why she's doing
what she's doing.
I just can't figure her out.
Well, there's no logic at work here,
Andy. Let that one go.
In the grand design,
women were drawn
from a different set of blueprints.
- Amen to that.
- Amen.
Hawk, Andy.
Rapid fire.
Hawk. Six for six, two kills.
High marks.
Andy.
Andy, what we need is practice
and lots of it.
One hour, three times a week.
Harry, you'll supply the ordnance?
Whatever it takes.
Chin up, Andy.
- You ever been married, Cooper?
- No.
I knew someone once who
helped me understand commitment,
the responsibilities and the risks.
Who taught me the pain
of a broken heart.
One woman
can make you fly like an eagle,
another can give you the strength
of a lion.
But only one in the cycle of life
can fill your heart with wonder
and the wisdom that you have known
a singular joy.
- I wrote that for my girlfriend.
- Local gal?
Diane Shapiro, Ph.D., Brandeis.
Harry, one miss, five hits, three kills.
Excellent.
Only four hits?
I put four through the eyes
and one through each nostril.
Nice pattern.
Agent Cooper, I'm
looking at the files from Dr. Lydecker's.
And for instance,
I have here in the A's an Arky,
who's a part poodle, part rottweiler
who lives on Maple
and belongs to Mr. Rumple.
Then, for example, I have an Annette,
who's an otter
who lives with a family
near Elk River.
We wanted the name of birds.
I know, but the files
are all organized alphabetically.
Lucy, go through the bird file.
No, no, you don't understand.
They're organized alphabetically
in the names of the pet.
We're gonna need
some more coffee.
Thanks, Toad. I'll be sure to get this
into my retirement fund ASAP.
Shelly, you're gonna
scare the customers.
I've got one man too many in my life,
and I'm married to him.
- Sound familiar?
- You should have a little talk with Leo.
Leo doesn't talk. He hits.
He was so great at first, you know?
This flashy guy in his hot car.
Then we get married,
and I find out all he was looking for
was a maid he didn't have to pay.
I feel so stupid.
Look at us.
Two men apiece,
and we don't know what to do
with any of the four of them.
So how did Hank's hearing go?
They're not gonna decide
till this afternoon.
Have you told him
you're divorcing him for Ed?
When I saw him, I, uh...
He might not even get out
this time around.
Guess my plans
are a little up in the air.
Yeah, well,
I've definitely got plans for Leo.
You know what we're gonna do,
Shelly?
Tomorrow you and I are gonna have
a day of beauty.
A manicure, a facial, we're gonna have
our hair done, the works.
We're gonna be the knockouts
of the Double R.
It's my treat.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Donna?
- Hi, James.
- Donna!
- Hold on.
Who the heck ever heard
of diet lasagna?
Just a sec, Daddy.
I'll be right in, okay?
- It's James.
- Hm.
Hi, we're having this
church potluck dinner here tonight.
Well, tell him
to get over here. I need help.
- SOS.
- Okay.
Mayday, mayday.
Would you like to come?
I don't think
I'd be very good company.
Well, I think we need to talk. Um...
I've found out some things.
Audrey told me some stuff
and Mrs. Palmer saw something.
- What?
- Well, if you come over, I can tell you.
I'm gonna get something to eat.
Then I'll be over in a little bit.
Okay. Bye.
Hi.
Who are you?
My name's Madeleine Ferguson.
- Laura was my cousin.
- James Hurley.
Laura and I hadn't
seen each other much recently.
I live in Missoula.
- Did you know Laura well?
- I thought I did. Heh.
Here you go.
I've got your order ready.
- Thanks a lot.
Mm-hm.
I'm picking up food
for my aunt and uncle.
Aunt Sarah can't cook right now,
and Uncle Leland's up half the night
listening to old music
and crying and stuff.
But if I was cooking for them,
they'd be doing even worse. Heh. Heh.
- Um, you think I look like Laura?
- Yes.
We used to come visit Twin Peaks
when I was a kid.
It was great.
We'd pretend we were sisters.
I wish I'd known her better.
It's so sad.
Well, it was nice to meet you,
James Hurley.
Nice to meet you too.
Thanks for calling, Mr. Mooney.
Are you okay?
Hank got his parole.
He's coming home.
What's that?
No, I don't know what you get when
you cross a Norwegian and a Swede.
Oh, very good, sir, very good.
I can't tell you how excited we are
about bringing Icelandic investment
to the great Northwest.
Would you put my brother
back on, please?
Jerry, who the hell is that joker?
You're sure that he's the boss?
Just make sure they don't start
taking eggnog in to the pilot.
Jer, I've got the jet gassed up
and on the runway in Seattle.
Usher these guys through customs,
make your connection,
and save me some of whatever it is
that they're having. Ha-ha.
Yeah.
Oh, Audrey.
I didn't hear you come in.
What is it this time?
Dad, are you ashamed of me?
Audrey, you're, uh...
You're my daughter.
I was thinking about
what we talked about the other night
when you were so mad.
It isn't that I'm ashamed of you,
Audrey.
It's just that I wish
I could depend on you more,
especially during a trying time
like this.
Well, that's what I wanted
to talk to you about.
Dad, I wanna change my life.
I've decided I wanna help you
with the family business.
I mean, one of these days
you'll need someone to take over,
and obviously
it's not gonna be Johnny.
Heh-heh. Oh, Audrey,
I wish that I could believe you.
Daddy, please.
I saw a friend of mine cut down like
a flower that had just begun to bloom.
Life can be so short.
There isn't all the time in the world,
I see that now,
and I wanna change my life.
How, exactly?
I don't need to go to college.
You can teach me the business,
and I'm willing to start
at the absolute bottom.
All right.
We've got some guests arriving.
You go upstairs
and start making some beds.
You still don't believe me?
All right. Okay.
Okay. All right, all right.
Where would you start?
Well, I think I should start
at the department store.
Cosmetics or something.
Just part-time at first, till I graduate.
You're really serious, aren't you?
You have to start to think about
the future, Daddy, just like I am.
- The future?
- Our family's future.
Please let me be
your daughter again.
Audrey...
Hello, this is Benjamin Horne.
Uh...
I have to take this, sweetheart.
Oh, okay.
Thanks, Daddy.
Thank you, Audrey.
Where have you been?
Meet me down by the river
in a half-hour.
And be discreet.
Here's a bird. Louis Armstrong.
He's a parakeet.
Put it with the others.
Agent Cooper,
I've got Gordon Cole on the phone.
- Cooper here.
- Coop,
Albert is faxing you his reconstruction
of the plastic object
found in Laura Palmer's stomach.
He's also determined the bites and
marks on her shoulders were made
by a parrot or a myna bird.
That's it. You're up to date.
- Take a look at this.
- Something with the letter J.
Poker chip.
One-Eyed Jack's.
Waldo!
Harry, Agent Cooper,
it's a myna bird named Waldo.
A myna bird
owned by Jacques Renault.
I'll get his home address.
Gentlemen, when two separate events
occur simultaneously
pertaining to the same object
of inquiry,
we must always pay strict attention.
Fellas, let's make a house call.
Nice game.
Jacques, it's Harry Truman.
Open the door.
- He's headed around the side.
- Go get him.
Let's get Forensics
and seal this room, Harry.
- Harry?
- Yeah, Hawk.
He got away from me.
I lost him in the woods.
Harry?
"L.J." Leo Johnson.
Leo Johnson and Jacques Renault.
That's our connection.
Hm?
Nice touch, Leo, nice touch.
Bright-red sports car
for a secret meeting. Nice.
- You don't like it, get somebody else.
- Oh, no, no.
Hank said that you were gifted.
I believed him.
But, Leo, your whole approach,
it's misguided.
Major career opportunity
staring you in the face,
and all you can think about is car wax
and chicken-feed drug transactions.
Hey, I'm out $10,000. Maybe
that's peanuts to you, not to me.
You were in business with a couple
glue-sniffing squish-heads, Leo.
The Renault brothers?
I broke up their act.
This is Bernie.
Jacques is back in Canada.
We had a long talk.
He's staying there.
Jacques was the brains in the outfit.
Bernie made bail this morning
on possession.
Ahem. And do we know
if, uh, the late Bernard gave you up?
I told him if he ever did, I'd kill him.
Oh, and did he?
No, he shouldn't have trusted me,
but like I said, Bernie wasn't too bright.
Okay. One last chance, Leo.
Don't disappoint me.
- The mill?
- Keep it simple.
Insurance investigator should read
arson, block letters, about 6 feet high.
The deal as we discussed?
The rest on delivery.
Three nights, Leo. Green light.
Is that clear enough?
But if Mrs. Palmer
knows about the necklace...
- How? How could she know?
- She said she saw it.
She said she had a vision
and she saw someone take it.
Donna.
Donna, it's not here.
Somebody must have seen us.
Somebody must have followed us here.
How?
How could Mrs. Palmer know?
Laura used to say
her mother was kind of spooky.
She used to see things.
She had these dreams.
Laura did too.
- Maybe we should tell somebody.
- You mean the police?
Well, if it was the killer,
then he knows that we know.
James, the police didn't love Laura.
Nobody loved her but us.
I keep thinking I'm gonna see her.
I think that, you know,
I'm gonna catch a glimpse of her
out of the corner of my eye.
Sometimes it's like
I really do see her.
James, listen.
We're gonna find out who killed her.
This is about us.
We have to do this for us,
not just for her.
James, I wanna be with you.
Hello?
Josie, it's me.
Hi.
We just got a break
in the Palmer case. I can't get away.
- I miss you. I need to talk to you.
- I wanna talk to you too.
Josie, were you at the
Timber Falls Motel this afternoon?
Eh, I have to go.
Um, call me tomorrow?
Goodbye.
Blow the whistle, Josie.
It's quitting time.
How did the shift go, Pete?
Oh, cut some wood,
made some lumber.
- I'm so tired, I could...
- You could eat a horse?
- I made you a turkey sandwich.
- Oh, that's fantastic, Josie.
- Uh, is Catherine asleep?
- Yeah.
Good, then give me some mayo
with that.
Josie, uh, how do you feel about fish?
- To eat?
- No, to catch.
See, the Fishing Association,
their annual do is coming up,
and, uh, I'm defending champion.
And this year, well, they're adding
a mixed-doubles division,
and I thought, well,
if you were interested, uh,
what the heck, uh, would you like to,
uh, partner up with me?
Well, Pete, I don't know the first step
about fishing.
Oh, Josie, there's enough
fishing in me for the both of us.
- Well, what do you think?
- Sure, Pete.
Let's give it the run at the money.
Josie, you're my kind of gal.
Here. I'm gonna hit the hay.
- Sweet dreams, Pete.
- Sweet dreams, Josie.
Hello.
Did you get my message?
Yes.
Catch you later.