Diane, 6:18 a.m., Room 315.
Great Northern Hotel
up here in Twin Peaks.
Slept pretty well. Non-smoking room.
There's no tobacco smell.
That's a nice consideration
for the business traveler.
A hint of Douglas fir needles
in the air.
As Sheriff Truman
indicated they would,
everything this hotel promised,
they've delivered.
Clean, reasonably priced
accommodations.
Telephone works.
Bathroom in really tiptop shape.
No drips, plenty of hot water
and good, steady pressure.
That could be a side benefit
of the waterfall outside my window.
Mattress firm, but not too firm.
And no lumps like that time
I told you about down in El Paso.
What a nightmare that was.
But you've heard me
tell that story once or twice,
haven't you, Diane?
Haven't tried the television set yet.
Looks like cable,
probably no reception problems.
But the true test of any hotel,
as you well know, Diane,
is that morning cup of coffee,
which I'll be getting back to you
about within a half hour.
Diane, it struck me again
earlier this morning.
There are two things
that continue to trouble me
and I'm speaking now
not only as an agent of the Bureau,
but also as a human being.
What really went on between
Marilyn Monroe and the Kennedys?
And who really pulled the trigger
on JFK?
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
You know, this is, excuse me,
a damn fine cup of coffee.
I've had I can't tell you how many cups
of coffee in my life and this...
This is one of the best.
Now, I'd like two eggs, over hard.
I know, don't tell me,
it's hard on the arteries.
But old habits die hard.
Just about as hard
as I want those eggs.
Bacon, super crispy, almost burned.
Cremate it.
That's great.
And I'll have the grapefruit juice.
Just as long as those grapefruits...
...are freshly squeezed.
My name's Audrey Horne.
Federal Bureau of Investigation
Special Agent Dale Cooper.
Can I sit here?
Well, Miss Horne,
unless I miss my guess,
your father is Benjamin Horne,
the owner of this fine establishment.
So I imagine you can sit
anywhere you'd like.
I'd also like to add
it would be my pleasure.
Thank you.
You're here investigating
the murder of Laura Palmer?
Were you friends with Laura Palmer?
Not exactly.
See, Laura tutored my older brother,
Johnny, three times a week.
Johnny's 27
and he's in the third grade.
He's got emotional problems.
Runs in the family.
Do you like my ring?
Very nice.
You know, sometimes
I get so flushed, it's interesting.
Do your palms ever itch?
Morning, deputy. Hey, Lucy.
Good morning, Agent Cooper.
Agent Cooper,
I got jelly for you special.
The sheriff's in the conference room.
It's the door across from the...
I'll look for him
in the conference room.
Hey, three for three.
Sheriff, let's get James Hurley up
from cell 4 and talk to him straight.
He was in love with Laura Palmer.
My bet is she told him whatever dirt
she knew about Mike and Bobby
and who knows what else.
Then let's have a little chat
with those two perpetrators.
Let's run a top-to-bottom on Bobby's
vehicle, see what that brings us.
Also check on the autopsy
on Laura Palmer
and see what that brings in.
We're also gonna wanna talk
to Mr. and Mrs. Palmer,
let's give them a few days
to deal with their grief.
I've got the rest of our day mapped out,
let's meet back here in three minutes.
Harry, I really have to urinate.
Oh. By the way,
coffee at the Great Northern?
Incredible.
Harry, as you know,
I delivered Laura.
I've known her all her life.
She was my daughter's best friend.
I couldn't bring myself
to do the postmortem,
so I called Joe Fielding in
from Fairvale.
He did the work, I assisted.
Well, this is what he found.
Time of death estimated
to be between midnight and 4 a.m.
What killed her is loss of blood.
Numerous shallow wounds,
no single one serious enough
to have caused death.
Bite marks on her shoulders,
also on her tongue.
Probably self-inflicted.
Lesions on wrists, ankles, upper arms,
where she was bound.
We're waiting on the toxological tests
for drug use.
Within the last 12 hours,
she'd had sexual relations
with at least three men.
You've examined
Ronnette Pulaski as well?
Yes, sir.
There's no question in my mind.
The same perpetrator attacked
both of them in that train car.
Doc, when, if ever,
will Ronnette be able to talk to us?
She had a severe head injury,
it's still early to tell.
Add to that
the psychological impact of the fear,
probably witnessing what was
happening to Laura before she...
So beautiful.
Who would do a thing like that?
Leo.
Leo, honey, I have to go to work now
and Norma should be here any sec.
Leo?
Did you finish cleaning my boots?
Yeah, I did them
and I did the laundry too.
All of it?
Well, yeah.
No, you didn't.
Okay, Leo, when I get home,
I'll do it.
Now, Shelly.
Okay.
Blood.
Shelly? Norma's here.
Shelly, did you hear me say
Norma's here?
Yeah, I heard you, Leo.
I'm gonna come by the diner
sometime today.
Be a good girl
and save me a piece of pie.
Sure, Leo.
James, you were placed under arrest
for suspicion of murder.
The murder of Laura Palmer.
Now, you have no previous
criminal record, is that correct?
None. No, sir.
Did you shoot this video?
That's your cycle, isn't it?
Yes, sir.
The three of us went up there
two Sundays ago.
James, you were in love with Laura.
The two of you
were seeing each other secretly.
No one else at school
or any of her friends knew about it.
She was the homecoming queen,
she was dating the captain
of the football team.
How much longer did you think
you could keep this relationship
a secret?
Yeah, well, it was secret
because that's the way she wanted it.
Why? Was she afraid of Bobby?
I think so.
Did you know
she was using cocaine?
Yes.
Did you ever use cocaine with her?
No, I tried to get her to stop.
- And she did for a while.
- Why did she start using again?
Something happened
a couple of days ago.
What? What happened?
I don't know.
I think something scared her
because she wouldn't see me.
She wouldn't even talk to me.
When was the last time you saw her?
The night she died.
She snuck out of her house
about 9:30.
About 12:30, I stopped the bike
at the light at Sparkwood and 21.
And she jumped off and ran away.
I didn't see her again.
Did you and Laura have a fight?
Not exactly.
But she said
she couldn't see me anymore.
Why?
She didn't say.
You recognize this necklace?
Yes, sir.
James, what happened
on February 5th?
And who has the other half
of this heart?
James, guess why
I'm so happy today.
Because your skin is so soft
and you smell so good?
- No.
- Why?
Because I really believe
that you love me.
Now my heart belongs to you.
I don't know.
Damn it.
Where's that shirt?
No!
Hey, Bopper.
Since when does Leo Johnson
call me at my parents' house?
Leo called you?
Yeah, yesterday.
He was looking for you.
He wanted to know where
the other half of the money was.
What did you tell him, Snake?
Well, as far as I knew,
he didn't have any of it yet.
Because I thought the deal was
we were supposed to give it to him
today.
Yeah, well,
I gave him half already.
When did you see him?
- Hey, I saw him the other night, okay?
- What night?
The night Laura died.
I went to see Leo
because I had this money burning
a $10,000 hole in my pocket.
What about the other half?
- It's in Laura's safe-deposit box.
- So you didn't get it back from her?
She was supposed
to hand it over today.
Then she went
and checked out on us.
So how are we supposed to get
10 grand for Leo?
I don't know, Snake.
Maybe we could sell light bulbs
door to door.
Oh, that's great, that's just...
That's just great.
- This isn't funny, Bobby.
- I'm not laughing.
We're lucky.
We're lucky we're in jail.
Because you know what's gonna go
down with Leo when we get out.
Shut up, man.
Don't mention one word
about Leo Johnson.
You do not know Leo Johnson.
Help me.
Mom.
Hi, honey.
Mom, it's 10:30.
Why didn't you wake me?
I was supposed to go
to the sheriff's office.
They called this morning
and said they could wait
until tomorrow to see you.
Your father and I thought
you needed your rest.
You woke us crying in your sleep
last night.
- Do you remember?
- No.
Really?
We feel so badly for you.
We're so sorry.
Mom, it's so strange.
I know I should be sad, and I am.
Part of me is.
But it's like...
It's like I'm having
the most beautiful dream
and the most terrible nightmare
all at once.
Your father said
you went out last night
to meet a boy named James Hurley.
Does this have anything to do
with him?
Can this be between you and me?
Of course it can.
James and Laura were seeing
each other the last two months.
I was the only one
who knew about it.
Mom, James was so good for her.
You don't know how troubled
Laura was.
Last night, I had to see him.
We were the two closest people
in the world to her.
But I feel so bad now.
Why, angel?
Because we realized...
...that all this time...
...we were the ones falling in love.
So I feel like
I've betrayed my best friend.
And if it's true,
then why am I so happy?
Oh, honey.
Now, you tell me what you wanna do.
Should we see these guys
separately or together?
- No, no, we can see them together.
- Okay.
Hey, Ed.
- How's that coconut?
- Well, it's kind of tender.
But my pride hurts worse.
Ed, this is Special Agent Dale Cooper.
- Pleasure.
- Any relation to James?
I'm his uncle
and he works in my garage.
His mother's out of town
and I look after him when she's away.
You fellas plan on holding him?
No, we can, uh,
release him into your custody.
Well, let me understand.
Is James being charged?
Well, I had one small doubt
which he cleared up for me.
He didn't kill anybody.
But you tell him to be careful
because we're gonna have to release
Mike and Bobby today as well.
- Will do.
- Agent Cooper,
I've got a call for you
from a Mr. Albert Rosenfield.
Sounds like long distance.
- Excuse me.
- Sure.
It has that open air sound, you know,
where it sounds like wind blowing?
- Like wind blowing through trees.
- Yes, Albert.
Harry, I've been thinking
about last night at the Roadhouse.
And something's not right.
Yeah, when I first saw that bandage,
I thought maybe old Nadine
caught wind of you and Norma.
Harry, if Nadine got wind of me
and Norma,
I'd be playing harp
for the Heavenly All-Stars.
Ain't that the truth?
I was there seeing Norma,
but I was also on my stakeout.
And I can remember Mike and Bobby
grabbing Donna
and I got up to walk over
and I got all lightheaded.
I was out on my feet
before I got there.
I don't even remember getting hit.
What do you mean
you don't remember?
Well, I'm pretty sure
my beer was drugged.
Jacques Renault was tending bar.
All right, Albert, bring the boys.
You can have the body
all day tomorrow.
No, I can't do it, they're gonna put her
in the ground on Monday.
Albert, listen.
If you come up through Lewis Fork,
I can recommend a place for lunch.
The Lamplighter Inn.
They got a cherry pie there
that'll kill you.
- Hi, Nadine.
- What are you doing here, Norma?
I might ask you the same question.
And I will tell you.
I've gotten all new drapes
for my house.
Ed bought them for me yesterday
at Gentleman Jim's.
And we installed them together.
They're a beige sheer.
I was up all last night.
Do you know what I was doing?
No, I don't.
I was inventing a noiseless,
completely silent drape runner.
And do you know how it works?
Do you know what makes it work?
The thing I thought of
at 4 this morning
when I was waiting for my husband
to be released from intensive care?
Cotton balls.
By God,
those things will be quiet now.
Did you have to post bail?
No, I had a talk with Harry.
There's no charge.
Mom still out of town?
Yeah, she's still out of town.
Let's get out of here.
Gonna need a hand
from the Bookhouse Boys.
- Somebody's gotta watch my back.
- Already got it covered.
Hi, Mike.
Bobby.
Well, before we get started, have you
two fellas got your stories straight?
If we tell the truth, we don't have
to get our stories straight.
Besides, the sheriff told us
we're just in here for fighting.
And, uh, it was self-defense.
Right.
Well, I guess you can go, then.
- Now?
Mm-hm.
Oh, fellas, one more thing.
Pray for the health and safety
of James Hurley
because if anything happens to him,
we're coming for you.
Sheriff,
what are you sitting around for?
We got places to go
and people to see.
Yeah, I think I better start
studying medicine.
Why's that?
Because I'm beginning to feel
a bit like Dr. Watson.
On top of the morning to you, Pete.
Uh, no, Josie, the expression
is "top of the morning."
And it's just barely morning.
Pete,
I want to thank you for yesterday.
For standing up to me with Catherine.
Forget it.
Catherine was wrong yesterday.
- Period.
- Well, thank you anyway.
- Hello.
- Pete, it's Harry.
I got Agent Cooper with me.
We're here to see Mrs. Packard.
Um, I will make a fresh pot of coffee.
- Hi, sheriff.
- Mrs. Packard.
Dale Cooper, FBI.
You remember him from
the town meeting last night, I'm sure.
Pleased to meet you, ma'am.
Agent Cooper,
you remember Pete Martell.
- Sure, Pete.
- You bet.
Uh, can we offer you gentlemen
a cup of joe?
Mrs. Packard,
you said the magic word.
- I'd love a cup, thanks.
- Sure, I'll pour that for you.
Uh, Mr. Cooper, uh,
how do you take it?
Black as midnight
on a moonless night.
Pretty black.
- Um, please sit down.
- Thank you.
Mrs. Packard,
I'll come straight to the point.
Mrs. Packard, I understand
that you hired Laura Palmer
to come visit you twice a week to help
you with your English, is that correct?
Yes.
When was the last time
that you saw her?
Thursday afternoon,
about the time the mill blew 5.
- That would be 5:00?
- Yes.
And when did she leave?
In an hour,
when the lesson was finished.
I didn't see her again.
How did she seem to you
on Thursday afternoon?
Something was bothering her.
But we didn't have
a heart-to-heart on it.
Something she said though,
that stuck on my mind.
She said,
"I think now I understand how you feel
about your husband's death."
Did she say
what that was in reference to?
No.
But after what happened to her,
I can't help hearing it in my head.
Like some haunting melody.
Hmm.
- Excuse me.
- Certainly.
So, Harry,
how long you been seeing her?
How did you know?
Body language.
Jeez Louise.
Not long. Six weeks.
Andrew died a year and a half ago.
Fellas, don't drink that coffee.
You'd never guess.
There was a fish in the percolator.
Sorry.
Yes, Catherine, I'm listening.
I just thought you ought to know
what your sentimental, goodwill
shenanigans cost us yesterday.
You do know what shenanigans are,
don't you?
Shutting down the mill
cost us $87,000 and change.
You really think that would have made
brother Andrew happy.
Jocelyn? Mrs. Packard?
Uh, what is "shenanigans?"
Nonsense, mischief,
often a deceitful or treacherous trick.
Why do you always have
to rush off?
It's been over an hour.
I remember there was a time
when we used to take
the whole afternoon.
In the sweetness of passing time,
this hour will soon seem like a day.
Sing it to somebody else.
I'm no peabrain chambermaid
looking for a tumble
in the broom closet.
I'm sorry.
Didn't mean to offend
your delicate sensibilities.
Oh, no. My mistake.
I'd gotten used to our
conducting business and pleasure.
Sweetheart,
it's all the same to me.
Don't "sweetheart" me, you old dog.
I'm no schoolgirl either.
What's the next step?
Do we escalate?
We may not have to do anything.
A few more, uh, local tragedies
and Josie might just run the old mill
into the ground all by herself.
The rate we're going, it's gonna be
years before the mill's bankrupt.
I don't wanna wait any longer.
Besides, my knothead husband
may peek in the ledger
and sniff out the creative arithmetic.
Maybe it's time to, uh,
start a little fire.
Are you talking about business
or pleasure?
I'm talking about
the Packard sawmill.
All that dry timber lying around.
A stray spark.
One night.
Some night when Pete's off on a toot
with Smokey the Bear.
Now I remember...
...how all those hours
turned into days.
Sarah, darling.
I'm sorry to disturb you, sweetheart,
but, uh, Donna Hayward is here.
Take this now.
I'll send her in.
- Try not to upset her.
- Okay.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
I miss her so much.
Do you miss her?
Yes, I miss her so much.
I miss her so much.
Laura.
Oh, Laura, my baby.
Oh. Oh.
Leland, Leland.
So neither of you saw Ronnette
after school that day?
That's right.
And as far as you know,
she went to her after-school job?
Yes, Horne's Department Store
downtown.
What did she do
at the department store?
She was, uh, a salesgirl.
At perfume counter.
She used to joke it was the
sweetest smelling job she'd ever had.
Excuse me.
How many times have I asked you
not to disturb the guests
with this racket?
About 4000.
Audrey,
Julie tells me that, uh,
you were in with the Norwegians
just before they all suddenly decided,
en masse,
to return to the old country...
...without signing the contracts.
Is that true?
- Yes.
- Ah.
You wouldn't have, uh,
done or said anything
that, uh, might have precipitated
their evacuation, would you?
I mean, I'm assuming
that this was just a coincidence.
- Huh?
- Daddy.
I did go in there to check out
that ridiculous smorgasbord.
And while I was in there,
I happened to mention that I was sad.
About what?
About my dear, close friend Laura
being brutally murdered.
Do you realize
the kind of money that your
little performance just cost this family?
If you ever pull
another stunt like that,
you are going to be scrubbing bidets
in a Bulgarian convent.
Oh, Daddy, I'm so afraid.
Laura died two days ago.
I lost you years ago.
For what we are about to receive,
may the Lord make us truly thankful.
Amen.
Robert, uh, I was hoping
we'd have the chance
to discuss the events
of the past few days.
Not necessarily
the physical events themselves,
but rather, the thoughts
and feelings surrounding it.
Rebellion in a young man your age
is a necessary fact of life.
Candidly, a sign of strength.
In other words, Robert,
I respect your rebellious nature.
However, being your father,
I am obligated to contain
that fire of contrariness
within the bounds
established by society
as well as those
within our own family structure.
Robert, I note your reluctance to enter
into a dialogue with me, your father.
There are times
when silence is golden.
Silence can be taken many ways,
as a sign of intelligence.
The quieter we become,
the more we hear.
Ah!
Now, I am a tolerant man.
My patience has its limits.
To have his path made clear
is the aspiration of every human being
in our beclouded
and tempestuous existence.
Robert, you and I are going to work
to make yours real clear.
We're here for you, Bobby.
Can I get you anything
to go with that, sheriff?
Agent Cooper here might wanna try
a slice of that pie.
- Cherry pie?
- Best in the tri-counties.
Hmm.
And could you ask Norma
to stop by a second, Shelly?
- Sure thing.
- Nothing's a sure thing, Shelly.
Man, I still can't get the taste
of that fish-filtered coffee
- out of my mouth.
- Me neither.
- That's Shelly Johnson, with a J?
- Mm-hm.
Husband's a trucker, Leo.
Minor rap sheet.
Log Lady?
- Right.
- Hi.
Can I ask her about her log?
Many have.
Evening, Harry.
Norma, like to have you meet
Special Agent Dale Cooper.
Federal Bureau of Investigation.
Norma Jennings.
Miss Jennings, is it true
that Laura used to help you
with the Meals on Wheels program,
delivering hot dinners
to elderly shut-ins?
Yeah, Laura helped organize
that program.
Do you have the names of the people
on her route?
- I can get them for you.
- Mm. Would you, please?
And, uh, two more pieces
of this incredible pie.
Okay.
Man, oh, man, you must have
the metabolism of a bumblebee.
For your information,
I heard you speaking
about Laura Palmer.
Yes.
One day, my log will have
something to say about this.
My log saw something that night.
Really? What did it see?
Ask it.
I thought so.
Thanks, Norma. See you tomorrow.
Hi, Leo.
Brought you some pie.
Where's my shirt?
What shirt?
My favorite blue shirt.
It's the second one
you lost this year.
I'm gonna teach you a lesson now,
Shelly,
about taking care of my property.
That means making sure
things aren't lost or damaged.
Oh, God, please, Leo.
- This is gonna hurt you.
- No.
No!
I'll get it.
Come on.
Uh, Mom, Dad, this is James.
James Hurley.
- How do you do, James?
- Nice to see you, sir, Mrs. Hayward.
Very nice to meet you, James.
Well, I hope you're hungry.
- Eileen's been cooking up a storm.
- Yes, sir.
Would you like something to drink?
We have some soft drinks
and some fruit punch,
some sparkling cider.
Uh, fruit punch.
That'd be good, thank you.
- I'll get it.
- Okay.
Uh, why don't you fellas
sit down at the table
and I'll go check on the roast.
- Here's your fruit punch.
- Thanks, Donna.
I don't believe
I know your parents, James.
No, sir. My dad died when I was 10
and my mom travels a lot.
- She writes for the paper sometimes.
- Oh.
Ed Hurley down at the Gas Farm
is James' uncle.
His, uh,
wife's the lady with the patch.
Yes, sir, that's my Aunt Nadine.
She's a real character.
Will? Could you come
give me a hand, please?
Uh, excuse me.
We can talk after dinner.
It's good to see you.
It's good to see you too.
That bastard.
First your girlfriend, then mine.
Too bad we can only kill him once.
Hey, what's up, doc?
It's Laura Palmer
in case you haven't guessed.
I'm making you
another one of these tapes,
which, as you already know,
I've mailed to you
in one of the envelopes you gave me.
It's Thursday the 23rd
and I'm so bored.
Actually,
I'm in kind of a weird mood.
God, James is sweet,
but he's so dumb.
I should have met you
a long time ago, Dr. Jacoby,
because right now,
I can take just so much of sweet.
I just know I'm gonna get lost
in those woods again tonight.
I just know it.
Remember me telling you
about that mystery man?
Well...