Were you afraid, Punky?
I was on the stage at the Roadhouse,
and the lights went out.
I kept thinking:
"The lights are going out,
the lights are going out."
And then they did.
And it all went black,
and I kept thinking:
"It's so dark,
what about hand signals?
What good would they do us now?
And the baby, what if the lights
went out in the hospital
and we were in the elevator?"
Then I'd help you have that baby
right there in the elevator,
in front of God and everybody.
- I love you.
Coop, I've got deputies
from three counties looking for Earle.
He seems to have
completely disappeared.
Harry, the only hope we have
of finding them
is somewhere in this map.
Giant, little man,
fire, fire walk with me.
Fire walk with me.
Grand theft auto.
The Log Lady stole my truck.
'68 Dodge pickup.
Powder blue.
I tried to chase after her,
but she took off
on the road up towards the woods.
Pete, the Log Lady
did not steal your truck.
The Log Lady will be here
in one minute.
The woods, Harry,
- Ghostwood forest.
- Ghostwood?
Twelve rainbow trouts in the bed.
Twelve.
Wait a doggone minute.
There's a circle of 12 sycamores.
Glastonbury Grove.
Sycamores.
That's where I found the bloody towel
and the pages of the diary.
The legendary
burial place of King Arthur.
Glastonbury.
King Arthur's buried in England.
Well, last I heard anyway.
Right on time.
It's the Log Lady.
Where's my truck?
Pete, Windom Earle stole your truck.
I brought the oil.
Thank you, Margaret.
It sure looked to me like you.
Margaret,
what did your husband
say exactly about this oil?
He brought it back one night
just before he died and said:
"This oil is an opening to a gateway."
Intriguing, isn't it?
Jacoby.
- Scorched engine oil.
Hawk, bring in Ronette Pulaski.
Ronette, thanks for coming in.
Do you recognize this smell?
Yes.
The night Laura Palmer was killed.
Glastonbury Grove.
I am Windom Earle.
Windom Earle?
Take a look at that.
Twelve rainbow trout.
If you're gonna kill me,
get it over with.
There's plenty of time for that.
But I do like the fear I'm feeling.
Our bones are scattered
at the grave's mouth,
as when one cutteth
wood upon the earth.
But mine eyes are unto thee,
O God the Lord:
in thee is my trust;
leave not my...
Keep me from the snares
they have laid for me,
and the gins of the workers
of iniquity.
Let the wicked fall into their own nets,
whilst that I withal escape.
What are we doing here?
You and I have an appointment
at the end of the world.
- He'll come for me.
- No, he won't.
- Why are you doing this to me?
- Same thing happened last time.
When he fell in love with my wife.
I took the boy right to the edge
that time.
Come in, come in to the circle!
I tell you, they have not died.
Their hands clasp, yours and mine.
You'll not run from me now,
not in this circle of trees.
You'll come with me.
Remember, 20 minutes on
and 20 minutes off with the ice bag.
It'll help with the swelling,
both of you.
Take some aspirin,
call me in the morning.
Thanks, doc.
Oh. Does it hurt much, baby?
God, Nadine,
I was so worried about you.
I admit there were times
when I had my doubts
about what we meant to each other,
but seeing that sandbag hit you,
I just knew
I'd practically do anything for you.
And then the tree hit me.
I love you.
There, I've said it and I'm glad.
Who are you?
Mike.
You...
You try to...
You say your name is Mike?
What are you doing in my house?
You brought me here, Nadine.
No!
No, you get out of here!
Ed, make him go away.
What's she doing here?
Oh.
It's not fair.
Please...
Ed, make...
Where are my drape runners?
Nadine, how old are you?
What kind of a stupid question
is that?
Answer me. How old are you?
Thirty-five, you moron!
I'm sorry, Ed.
I think I let things
get a little out of hand.
Oh, no. No.
Donna, please.
Donna, please, listen.
- I've heard enough!
- Please, just let me explain.
- Donna...
- Leave me alone!
It isn't your parents' fault. It's mine.
My parents?
Who are my parents anyway?
I only wanted to do good.
I wanted to be good.
And it felt so good to tell the truth
after all these years.
Ben, damn it.
- Will.
- Donna.
Ben, I warned you.
Get out of my house.
Will,
can you forgive me
for what I have done to you?
Sylvia, I told you to stay home.
What are you trying to do
to this family?
Daddy, you're my daddy.
You're my daddy.
Daddy.
Leave my family alone!
Now, Will. Will!
- Will!
- Unh!
No!
Ah. I knew I'd seen it somewhere.
Safety deposit box.
They'll never notice the difference.
Oh, Andrew.
Good night, Pete.
Harry,
this way.
Coop?
Harry, I have to go on alone.
Why?
What?
Oh.
Sycamore trees.
An opening to a gateway.
Footprints.
My God.
Under the sycamore tree
And I'll see you
And you'll see me
And I'll see you in the branches
That blow in the breeze
I'll see you in the trees
Under the sycamore tree
Sheriff Truman?
Andy! Over here!
Been about ten hours
since he went in there.
Do you want a thermos of coffee?
Yeah.
Do you want a plate special?
Do you want dessert?
Yeah.
Do you want pie?
Harry?
- Morning, Mr. Mibbler.
- Audrey Horne.
This is my fortunate day.
Is there anything I can do for you?
As a matter of fact, there is.
You can call the Twin Peaks Gazette.
Ask to speak
with Dwayne Milford Jr.
- Dwayne?
- The editor.
Eh?
Heh.
We must make a telephone call.
- Uh, yes?
- Yes.
Tell him that Audrey Horne
has chained herself
to the Twin Peaks
Savings and Loan vault
in protest of their financial ties
to the Ghostwood
Development Project.
And that I intend to stay here
until a town meeting is held
to debate the future
of our environment
and specifically the effect
of the Ghostwood Project upon it.
- Okay?
- Yeah, miss.
And can I get a glass of water,
please?
Uh... Uh...
Thank you, Dell.
You, you.
You!
Heh, heh. Dell Mibbler,
as I live and breathe.
He's alive.
But the funeral.
And all of the flowers,
and the choir boys.
I was hoping you could do
a small favor for me.
Does this look familiar to you?
Yes, it's one
of our safety deposit keys.
- Aha. Shall we?
- Well, of course.
But there is going to be
a bit of a problem.
A bit of a problem.
- Hi, Pete.
- Audrey?
Young lady, why are you
chained to the bank vault?
Civil disobedience.
Ah. Ha, ha.
Waste no time arguing
what a good man should be, be one.
Marcus Aurelius.
I admire your verve.
I see no problem here.
If you'll excuse us, please?
Sure.
Did you call the Gazette yet?
Maybe you should call the sheriff too.
Ask for Agent Cooper.
Give me the key.
A boy? It's a boy!
It's a boy, it's a boy.
- So long.
We've come to the end
of a long road, Pete.
And here we are.
Oh, sh...!
Mm.
Shelly, I think we should get married.
Bobby.
Leo. I'm still wearing his ring.
Oh, what kept us, Heidi?
Seconds on knackwurst
this morning?
I couldn't get my car started.
Too busy jump-starting the old man.
- Again.
I thought you Germans
were always on time.
- Shelly...
- Bobby.
Leo's probably up in the woods
having the time of his life.
Well, you were right,
there's the major.
Excuse us, Major Briggs,
for the intrusion,
but Sarah here had a message for you
that she thought was important.
Sarah.
I'm in
the Black Lodge with Dale Cooper.
I'm waiting for you.
[DISTORTED
Whoo!
Caroline.
Annie.
Annie!
Annie. Annie.
Annie?
Annie,
the face of the man who killed you?
Annie?
Caroline.
I will.
Cooper!
Annie!
Annie.
There he is.
Coop?
I wasn't sleeping.
Annie, how's Annie?
She's gonna be just fine.
She's over at the hospital.
I need to brush my teeth.
Sure. Come on.
I'll help you up.
Take her easy now.
I need to brush my teeth.
Good idea.
Coop?
Coop, are you okay?
How is Annie? How's Annie?
How's Annie?
How's Annie? How's Annie?